[{"question":"Which of the following is a benefit of collaborative transportation management (CTM)?","choices":["A. Reduction of carriers' wait time for loading and unloading ","  B. Optimization of weight and volume capacity of network resources ","  C. Increase in backhaul opportunities for carriers ","  D. All of the above  "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"CTMs can deliver all of these benefits by aligning transportation needs with transportation assets to eliminate inefficiencies, such as wait time, half-filled loads, or empty backhauls (\"deadheading\").  . "},{"question":"You are purchasing an item online and receive the following automated message: \"Other customers like you have also ordered X. Would you like to learn more about this product now? If so, click here.\" This is an example of","choices":["A. a win-back program. ","  B. a loyalty program. ","  C. cross-selling. ","  D. up-selling. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Cross-selling is a CRM tactic made possible by the accumulation of data about a customer's buying habits. Customers are offered related products in addition to their current purchase.  "},{"question":"The first step to successfully implement a strategic supplier alliance should be to","choices":["A. select the proper partners by evaluating corporate culture and operating style. ","  B. establish ground rules for how partners will work together and resolve conflict. ","  C. align internally by identifying key issues and stakeholders. ","  D. appoint a dedicated alliance manager to oversee the partner relationship. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Before entering alliances, start identifying key issues and decisions and involving key stakeholders for fewer surprises and greater buy-in by key people.  "},{"question":"After selecting the proper partner, the next step in creating a successful alliance is to","choices":["A. appoint an alliance manager. ","  B. engage in a collaborative corporate mindset. ","  C. negotiate a win-win deal. ","  D. establish ground rules. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Before the rules, supervision, and improvement of the relationship can be pursued, a win-win deal must be negotiated. This sets the tone for the future alliance.  "},{"question":"Companies outsourcing CRM should","choices":["A. transfer responsibility for CRM to vendors as a contractual obligation. ","  B. consider outsourcing core competencies. ","  C. develop an exit strategy. ","  D. encourage vendors to establish their own performance standards that will be meaningful to their own resources and culture. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The company outsourcing CRM should be the one to define the performance standards against which the vendor will be measured at regular intervals. CRM, after all, remains the responsibility of the outsourcing business, since these are their customers. These businesses should also maintain an exit strategy in case the relationship with the CRM vendor falters.  "},{"question":"In a CRM context, a product and service agreement (PSA)","choices":["A. is a type of customer communication. ","  B. aligns customer groups with certain service levels. ","  C. is part of a promotional strategy to win back customers. ","  D. defines product or service specifications.  "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A product and service agreement does define specifications, but it does so in the context of segmenting customer groups. Customers are mapped and then aligned with different levels of customer service.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is part of the definition of SRM?","choices":["A. Provides fuller communication without actual integration ","  B. Way to ensure mutual profitability while meeting marketplace needs ","  C. Tool to align the customer voice with the product produced ","  D. Philosophy applied equally to all suppliers "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"SRM focuses on the supply side of the supply chain to ensure that customer demands can be met with a high degree of satisfaction but also with mutual profitability for all suppliers. Relationships using SRM are marked by a high degree of integration of processes and even information systems. SRM may not be appropriate in relationships with all suppliers but rather with suppliers considered key partners in maintaining the supply chain. "},{"question":"An organization whose IT and operations groups are able to collaborate easily is best described as","choices":["A. farseeing. ","  B. change-oriented. ","  C. cross-functional. ","  D. able to lead. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A cross-functional organization is one that enjoys cooperation between internal groups, especially IT and operations. "},{"question":"CRM and SRM share a focus on","choices":["A. understanding buying habits of retail customers. ","  B. choosing appropriate strategic partners. ","  C. providing superior marketing decision support. ","  D. gathering and sharing information."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Both CRM and SRM focus on gathering information but for different purposes: CRM to understand customers better and support marketing, SRM to develop and manage relationships with key partners in the supply chain.  "},{"question":"SRM has been used in the parts/after-market industry to","choices":["A. implement both production and sales tactics. ","  B. gather information about customers. ","  C. retool aging technology. ","  D. select suppliers."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"SRM has been used in the parts or after-market industry to plan both strategy and tactics as well as to budget and manage specific business events, such as managing inventory.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about a customer data warehouse (CDW) is correct?","choices":["A. One-to-one marketing cannot be achieved without using a CDW. ","  B. CDWs are primarily used as measurement tools. ","  C. CDWs are maintained as separate entities from a company's customer databases. ","  D. None of the above "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Because it allows a high degree of customization, one-to-one marketing programs cannot be implemented without using a CDW. CDWs are used for a variety of purposes, including segmentation, implementing different offers to customers, analyzing buying behaviors to detect preferences, and supporting strategic decisions, such as the allocation of human resources. They are usually used in conjunction with information from a company's other databases. "},{"question":"A company maintains a secondary outsourced transportation network capable of meeting the needs of its primary customer base. This is an example of","choices":["A. outsourcing transportation needs. ","  B. using an off-site delivery center. ","  C. managing possible risks of SRM outsourcing. ","  D. poor outsourcing practices. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"It is reasonable to outsource transportation, especially in a global marketplace. And it is an especially sound practice to manage risks associated with this outsourcing by maintaining a redundant supplier in the event of disruptions with the primary outsourced transportation network. "},{"question":"A company fears that it will be overcome in the marketplace by a competitor who is developing a new technology that will give it dominance. In response, the company forms an alliance with a supply chain partner. They invest equally in creating the infrastructure to support the alliance, revise their corporate visions and organizational structure, and create processes to share information and merge workflows. Yet, the alliance may fail because it lacks","choices":["A. integration. ","  B. individual excellence. ","  C. information. ","  D. investment. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Successful alliances begin from a position of mutual strength and excellence. In this case, one partner is driven primarily by a desire to escape the problem of looming competition. This will be a hard obstacle to overcome even though the partners have invested in the relationship and integrated their organizations.  "},{"question":"\"Customer interest is high, and supply must be managed to meet demand and avoid stockouts that could boost growing competition.\" This sentence best describes what phase of the product life cycle?","choices":["A. Development ","  B. Introduction ","  C. Growth ","  D. Maturity"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"During the growth phase, the customer base increases and competitors begin to enter the market. Data on the growing customer base must be analyzed for new opportunities, and supply must be managed to meet growing demand.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the best example of risk mitigation in a strategic alliance?","choices":["A. Overcoming barriers to market entry. ","  B. Surmounting limited availability of component suppliers. ","  C. Improving overall financial position. ","  D. Improving operations by lowering system costs. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"From a purely reactive stance, companies with certain types of supply situations may be able to manage risk better in a strategic alliance. Purchasers must consider the strategic importance of the component, the complexity of the component-product interface, the number of component suppliers available, and the uncertainty of the supplier relationship.  "},{"question":"\"A variety of activities all designed to position what the business is selling to the right people, at the right time, and in the right manner.\" This describes which component of a CRM strategy?","choices":["A. Price ","  B. Promotion ","  C. Placement ","  D. Product "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Promotion comprises a variety of marketing activities, from customer research through strategy setting and advertising. CRM enhances both the gathering of information about customers and the use of that information in marketing activities. "},{"question":"Technological challenges facing supply chain integration efforts include which of the following?","choices":["A. Inability to customize off-the-shelf solutions ","  B. Difficulty in accessing information ","  C. Open system infrastructures ","  D. Underpowered, overly complex, or poorly designed solutions "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"As with any technological solution, systems may be underpowered, overly complex, poorly designed, or just not right for the job at hand. In general, more systems today are designed to be open, information is more accessible, and software solutions are more easily customized to specific settings "},{"question":"Which of the following is an enterprise business system (EBS) backbone application?","choices":["A. Managing online bidding sessions ","  B. Managing EDI with suppliers ","  C. Product cataloging ","  D. Order history"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"EBS backbone applications focus on gathering, storing, and reporting information that is necessary to perform other functions in the SRM system, such as data on order history and accounting and information about suppliers and their performance.  "},{"question":"Companies outsourcing CRM should","choices":["A. consider outsourcing core competencies. ","  B. encourage vendors to establish their own performance standards that will be meaningful to their own resources and culture. ","  C. develop an exit strategy. ","  D. transfer responsibility for CRM to vendors as a contractual obligation. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The company outsourcing CRM should be the one to define the performance standards against which the vendor will be measured at regular intervals. CRM, after all, remains the responsibility of the outsourcing business, since these are their customers. These businesses should also maintain an exit strategy in case the relationship with the CRM vendor falters. "},{"question":"In which type of customer segmentation are customers grouped by their relative profitability to the business?","choices":["A. Segmentation by demographics ","  B. Segmentation by value ","  C. Segmentation by channel ","  D. Segmentation by need "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Segmentation by value shows a CRM business which groups are most profitable to them so that they can focus marketing efforts on those customers.  "},{"question":"In a CRM context, a product and service agreement (PSA)","choices":["A. aligns customer groups with certain service levels. ","  B. is a type of customer communication. ","  C. defines product or service specifications. ","  D. is part of a promotional strategy to win back customers."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A product and service agreement does define specifications, but it does so in the context of segmenting customer groups. Customers are mapped and then aligned with different levels of customer service.  "},{"question":"Lifetime customers","choices":["A. can increase revenue but have a neutral effect on profit. ","  B. are common in commodity markets driven by price rather than value. ","  C. are increasingly more expensive for a business to maintain as they become more demanding. ","  D. have forged a win-win relationship with the business in question. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Lifetime customers have a win-win relationship with the businesses they frequent. The customers gain greater satisfaction while the business enjoys decreased marketing costs and increased revenue and profit potential. Lifetime customers are not common in markets competing on price rather than added value.  "},{"question":"Realigning an organization from product-focused to customer-focused requires which of the following changes?","choices":["A. Focusing all changes on how the sales and customer service departments, which come into direct customer contact, do business ","  B. Replacing the chief operations officer (COO) with a chief customer officer (CCO) ","  C. Analyzing each customer contact point to determine how key players can maximize the customer's experience ","  D. Lowering production and distribution costs in order to increase customer support and marketing expenditures  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Every customer contact point must be analyzed to identify key players within the organization who can affect customer satisfaction and to determine what they can do to maximize the customer's experience. This requires a high level of collaboration across sections of the organization and a clear articulation throughout the organization, to every member, of this new priority. "},{"question":"Which of the following is an example of the voice of the customer (VOC) technique?","choices":["A. Customer design groups ","  B. Collated comments of sales representatives calling on specific customer groups ","  C. Brief checkoff customer satisfaction surveys printed on invoices ","  D. Analysis of customer buying behaviors "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Customer design groups are an example of open-ended information gathering used by VOC to make complex customer perceptions more visible to a business. A brief checkoff survey does not capture complex information. Analysis of behaviors and analysis by others do not present the customer's own voice.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about the role of SRM in the supply chain model is correct?","choices":["A. It focuses on meeting demand. ","  B. It focuses on gaining information about customers. ","  C. It measures success only by satisfaction of end customers. ","  D. It helps ensure the same profitability for all supply chain elements."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"SRM helps ensure that demand created by CRM can be fulfilled in a manner profitable for all supply chain partners while maintaining customer satisfaction. Success of supplier relationships may be measured by various means, including time-to-market, cost efficiency, competitive advantage, and end customer satisfaction.  "},{"question":"You are purchasing an item online and receive the following automated message: \"Other customers like you have also ordered X. Would you like to learn more about this product now? If so, click here.\" This is an example of","choices":["A. cross-selling. ","  B. a win-back program. ","  C. up-selling. ","  D. a loyalty program. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Cross-selling is a CRM tactic made possible by the accumulation of data about a customer's buying habits. Customers are offered related products in addition to their current purchase.  "},{"question":"Which of the following best describes a customer data warehouse (CDW)?","choices":["A. Data about customers, products, and marketplace extracted from internal and external resources ","  B. Purchased data on specific customer segment ","  C. Repository of all data related to customer transactions ","  D. Current customer profiles stored in a database "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A customer data warehouse (CDW) stores data about customers, products, and market trends, consolidating it in a manner that can facilitate future analysis to spot trends and relationships.  "},{"question":"An SCM partner organization that undergoes internal restructuring to best align with the supply chain network before automating has asked which of the following key business questions?","choices":["A. What type of information is to be shared? ","  B. What business processes must change? ","  C. What application is optimal for all supply chain partners? ","  D. How will the supply chain partners collaborate? "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Automating business practices is typically expected to improve performance by eliminating manual processes. However, an organization will realize substantially more benefit if it first restructures its processes to best align with the supply chain network before automating.  "},{"question":"CRM and SRM share a focus on","choices":["A. providing superior marketing decision support. ","  B. choosing appropriate strategic partners. ","  C. understanding buying habits of retail customers. ","  D. gathering and sharing information."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Both CRM and SRM focus on gathering information but for different purposes: CRM to understand customers better and support marketing, SRM to develop and manage relationships with key partners in the supply chain. "},{"question":"Which of the statements about workflow management systems is correct?","choices":["A. They are a form of automated CRM. ","  B. They ensure consistency in implementing CRM policies. ","  C. They allow access to customer information and communications at critical service points. ","  D. All of the above"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Workflow management systems automate a sequence of steps and communications that must be completed to handle a customer situation. This is especially valuable when resolving a customer's problem may involve multiple company employees. Workflow management systems allow the system users to visualize the entire relationship and share the same information about the customer at all critical service points.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the key to enabling supply chains to more quickly respond to customer demand and increase participants' profitability?","choices":["A. Creating individual partnerships ","  B. Creating an alliance with a key supplier ","  C. Collaborative planning across the entire supply chain ","  D. Information sharing with key partners"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The key is collaborative planning across the supply chain rather than mere information sharing or single alliances.  "},{"question":"A \"best cost\" risk management outcome is derived by","choices":["A. multiplying the expected cost of the risk by its likelihood. ","  B. subtracting cost of possible risk from cost of business. ","  C. adding accumulated risk associated with all strategic suppliers. ","  D. subtracting cost of possible risk from cost of business and dividing that by likelihood of the occurrence. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A 'best cost\" analysis of risk is performed by multiplying the anticipated cost of the business disruption by the likelihood of its occurrence.  "},{"question":"Increased customer visibility means","choices":["A. knowing what each customer values. ","  B. being aware of each point of contact between the customer and the business. ","  C. seeing the transaction from the customer's viewpoint. ","  D. all of the above. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Increased customer visibility is a benefit of CRM in that CRM helps businesses to see each point of the purchasing transaction from the customer's perspective and to understand what the customer needs and values.  "},{"question":"Who promotes relationships between alliance partners, identifies opportunities for collaboration and improvement, and builds joint initiatives to capitalize on those opportunities?","choices":["A. Channel master ","  B. CEO ","  C. Alliance manager ","  D. Manager of purchasing "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The alliance manager is an individual whose job is to promote the alliance itself by sustaining relationships between partners, building joint initiatives, and bringing them to market to generate revenue and increase customers. "},{"question":"Which of the following is the best example of a promotion activity in a CRM strategy?","choices":["A. Charging less if a customer orders through the Internet ","  B. Segmenting customers according to their value to the business ","  C. Creating a product and service agreement (PSA) ","  D. Deciding where to distribute one's products"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Segmenting customers is an essential part of creating a promotional strategy, one of the four Ps of traditional marketing and CRM strategies. The other choices reflect those other components of a CRM strategy: product, price, and placement.  "},{"question":"Which of the following companies is most likely to be interested in SRM?","choices":["A. Paint manufacturer that purchases chemicals and dyes from various suppliers ","  B. Company that performs market research for political candidates ","  C. Credit card company ","  D. Company that produces video games "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Companies whose ability to meet customer demands rests on their control over the supply side of the supply chain model will be most interested in SRM. The other companies are primarily concerned with understanding and responding to customer needs and expectations.   "},{"question":"In a customer-focused organization, the starting point for new product development is","choices":["A. identifying customer need. ","  B. identifying a price point most acceptable to lifetime customers. ","  C. identifying a new market niche. ","  D. evaluating current customer product complaints. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"In a customer-focused world, the starting point for a product is often customer need.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about successful strategic supplier relationships is true?","choices":["A. Relationships should not be affected by the shifting priorities of the partners. ","  B. No single restructuring of processes will be adequate. ","  C. Although marketplace change may be constant, the details of the relationship should not change. ","  D. The best change occurs in large movements that motivate the entire organization rather than in smaller increments."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Supply partners must accept and commit to the fact of change in their relationships. As conditions and individual priorities and strategies change, the processes that define the relationship should change as well. It is better if change can be accomplished incrementally.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following is required for successful implementation of CRM and/or SRM strategies?","choices":["A. Greater control from the top down ","  B. Greater emphasis on task-focused responsibility centers ","  C. A new workforce ","  D. New job definitions"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Organizations implementing CRM and SRM must move toward greater collaboration and away from more hierarchical structures defined by task-focused responsibility centers and top-down decision making. They call for a new attitude and new skills in the existing workforce.  "},{"question":"An SCM partner organization that measures supply chain sales, shipments, and stockouts is adhering to which of the following collaborative principles?","choices":["A. Monitor performance. ","  B. Continuously improve. ","  C. Use supply chain assets collectively. ","  D. Understand the needs of the partners. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"An effective collaborative strategy must be measured to ensure its effectiveness. Processes and systems must be in place to monitor performance. Important measurements include supply chain sales, shipments, stockouts, invoicing, and payments.  "},{"question":"An external data network is","choices":["A. an outsourced CRM information management system. ","  B. a network resulting from collaboration between the information and communication systems of a company and other members of its supply chain. ","  C. an information repository for purchased customer data. ","  D. any information system outside the business from which it may have to extract customer data. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"External data networks are created through collaboration of partners in a supply chain and facilitate the exchange and analysis of information gathered at various points in the supply chain, from factory through distribution to call centers.  "},{"question":"A purchaser and its suppliers form an ongoing relationship in which they all participate in improving the system. This best exemplifies which of the following distinctions between traditional purchasing and strategic sourcing?","choices":["A. Limited visibility versus entire supply chain visibility ","  B. Transactional versus collaborative ","  C. Boundary-specific versus realigned work processes and workflows ","  D. Purchase price versus true cost "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Traditional purchasing sees each purchase as a discrete transaction. Since strategic sourcing involves ongoing relationships, there is opportunity for collaboration between the purchaser and suppliers that can result in improving the profitability of the supply chain and adding value to the final product or service.  "},{"question":"Why does market volatility create greater need for supply chain integration?","choices":["A. Integration enables a global response to demands. ","  B. Integration helps reduce conflicts of interest. ","  C. Integration helps counter consumers' and competitors' increased access to information. ","  D. Integration enables demand enhancement. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Consumers and competitors have more and faster access to information, causing market volatility. Supply chain integration provides comparable improvements in information access.   "},{"question":"Establishing clear ground rules for collaboration and conflict resolution benefits both alliance participants by","choices":["A. providing clear channels of legal redress for each participant. ","  B. preventing any sources of tension between participant organizations. ","  C. encouraging participants to redefine problematic connections rather than break them. ","  D. ensuring strict adherence to the established alliance contract by both participants"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"In a dynamic marketplace, a static consultant contract without clear and flexible guidelines and processes to manage the relationship simply encourages consultants to break their connection with the company rather than redefine it.  "},{"question":"\"A period marked by high costs and low sales.\" This phrase best describes what phase of the product life cycle?","choices":["A. Development ","  B. Introduction ","  C. Growth ","  D. Maturity"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Because of costs associated with marketing, establishing inventory, and developing the distribution system and because a customer base has not yet been acquired, the introduction phase of the product life cycle is marked by high costs but low sales.  "},{"question":"Which of the following factors has led to strategic sourcing and greater integration in the supply chain?","choices":["A. Shrinking global markets ","  B. Commodity pricing ","  C. Greater fragmentation on both sides of the supply chain ","  D. Decreasing customer response time "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Commodity pricing has made it more important for businesses to streamline the supply chain and become more cost-effective. The supply chain has, in fact, consolidated rather than fragmented; global markets have grown rather than shrunk. Consolidation may necessitate strategic sourcing as the number of sources narrows. Growing global markets present opportunities but also costs and risks that must be managed.  "},{"question":"In this long-term arrangement, suppliers are fully aware of the purchaser's goals and strategies and work with the purchaser to develop and implement tactics. This best exemplifies which of the following types of business relationships?","choices":["A. Buy the market ","  B. Ongoing relationship ","  C. Collaborations/strategic alliance ","  D. Mergers and acquisitions"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Collaborations or strategic alliances are long-term arrangements ruled more by agreements than contracts. The suppliers are fully aware of the purchaser's goals and strategies and work with the purchaser to develop and implement tactics. Trust levels are high. "},{"question":"Which of the following factors has led to greater customer focus in business?","choices":["A. Higher quality of goods and services ","  B. Advances in technology ","  C. Greater global competition ","  D. All of the above "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"All of the answers are correct. Higher quality, made possible through technology, has created increased customer expectations, which has in turn led to price as a differentiating factor. This has created a downward pressure on profit margin. Greater customer focus helps counter this pressure  "},{"question":"For which of the following companies would implementing SRM probably be most critical?","choices":["A. A company that uses raw materials and prefabricated components to create consumer goods ","  B. A gift catalog company that offers a large number of items from a wide variety of suppliers ","  C. A company competing in a commodity market with little opportunity for adding value ","  D. An Internet banking company seeking to expand use among high-value customers"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"SRM focuses on identifying opportunities for strategic relationships between supply chain partners and on developing and managing those relationships. The Internet banking company is concerned primarily with customers rather than suppliers. The commodity-driven company may have some benefit, but it will be limited by the opportunities to add value. Similarly, the gift catalog company requires adequate supply at the right times but may rely on so many suppliers that strategic partnerships are not practical. The manufacturer of consumer goods will benefit from developing strategic relationships with suppliers that add value and make its products more competitive.  "},{"question":"SRM is collaborative rather than transactional. Allowing suppliers to participate in improving the supply chain system benefits SRM participants in which of the following ways?","choices":["A. Cheaper products ","  B. Higher customer satisfaction ","  C. Reduced marketing costs ","  D. Increased control by the alliance manager "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"In SRM's collaborative relationships, suppliers can participate in improving the system, which results in better product, higher customer satisfaction, and better customer retention.  "},{"question":"Supply chain participant priorities often conflict. Which of the following groups sets a priority on product and feature variety and price reduction?","choices":["A. Customers ","  B. Manufacturers ","  C. Suppliers ","  D. Retailers "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Customers demand a variety of products and features as well as low prices.  "},{"question":"\"A technological advance that has led to both greater global competition and collaboration.\" This might best describe","choices":["A. advanced telephony features. ","  B. the intranet. ","  C. the computer. ","  D. the Internet. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"While the computer, intranets, and advanced telephony have certainly enhanced both supplier and customer relationship management, the Internet has made the largest impact on communication with customers and between partners in the supply chain.  "},{"question":"Successful implementation of CRM and SRM philosophies usually requires","choices":["A. redefinition of core competencies. ","  B. revision of decision-making processes. ","  C. common business goals and mission statements for all supply chain members. ","  D. outsourcing to companies with special expertise. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Implementing CRM and SRM does not require that companies change their core competencies, although employees may need to acquire new skills. Nor do organizations need to form common goals or mission statements. They will need, however, to revisit work processes, job definitions, and decision-making structures.  "},{"question":"Which of the following are current global forces shaping supply chain management strategies?","choices":["A. Increased influence of trade unions ","  B. Greater market volatility ","  C. Increased difficulties in communication and application sharing ","  D. Shrinking markets"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Companies are responding to the forces of globalization, increased project complexity, and greater market volatility by investing in technology that will enable them to better manage knowledge both within and across organizations.   "},{"question":"\"Voice of the customer\" refers to","choices":["A. a method of customer research. ","  B. a method of determining customer value. ","  C. a method of customer segmentation. ","  D. including customers in key marketing decisions"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The voice of the customer (VOC) is a customer research and measurement tool used to gain answers to complex marketing questions. VOC may include focus groups in which customers contribute to product or process design.  "},{"question":"Which one of these companies is practicing good SRM risk management?","choices":["A. This company develops detailed plans to shift work orders among several certified global suppliers in the event of labor disruptions in their countries. ","  B. This company sources a key raw material from one supplier who reliably provides the lowest price. ","  C. This company requires in its contracts that all suppliers use a defined third-party transportation provider for all shipments. ","  D. This company relies on the selection process as its only means of risk management. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Single sourcing of a key material or component is not a good example of risk management, even if the supplier is the lowest-cost provider. Good risk management may involve additional costs incurred through maintaining redundancy in the supply chain and requiring additional supplier performance or assumption of risk.  "},{"question":"Which of the following SRM activities might be outsourced successfully?","choices":["A. Selection of strategic partners ","  B. Setting corporate goals and developing strategy for alliances ","  C. Setting of procurement budgets ","  D. Contracting with strategic partners "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Many SRM tasks may be outsourced, from researching and contracting with alliance partners to development of technology. However, companies should never outsource strategic tasks or core competencies. "},{"question":"The first step to successfully implement a strategic supplier alliance should be to","choices":["A. align internally by identifying key issues and stakeholders. ","  B. appoint a dedicated alliance manager to oversee the partner relationship. ","  C. select the proper partners by evaluating corporate culture and operating style. ","  D. establish ground rules for how partners will work together and resolve conflict."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Before entering alliances, start identifying key issues and decisions and involving key stakeholders for fewer surprises and greater buy-in by key people. "},{"question":"Which of the following supply chain participants is likely to resist SCM efforts because they feel that e-marketplaces have the effect of reducing their products and services to a commodity?","choices":["A. Internal ","  B. Customer ","  C. Distributor ","  D. Supplier"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Many suppliers feel that e-marketplaces have the effect of reducing their products and services to a commodity where price is emphasized rather than quality or the partnership.   "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about technology and CRM/SRM is true?","choices":["A. Both CRM and SRM are essentially technological. ","  B. The effects of technology are more significant in SRM than CRM. ","  C. Technology plays a supporting role in CRM and SRM. ","  D. All of the above"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"While CRM and SRM are not synonymous with technical tools (they are philosophies and competitive strategies), they are both greatly supported by technological solutions.  "},{"question":"In a supply chain, distributors can refer customers to other distributors who have needed product on hand. This best describes a","choices":["A. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. ","  B. distributor integration (DI) network. ","  C. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network. ","  D. third-party logistics (3PL) company."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Using modern information and communication systems, distributor integration relationships allow distributors to share access to product and service.  "},{"question":"Supply chain participant priorities often conflict. Which of the following groups sets a priority on flexible delivery times, large volumes, and consistent materials mixes?","choices":["A. Warehouse managers ","  B. Retailers ","  C. Suppliers ","  D. Logistics managers"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Suppliers of raw materials typically prefer flexible delivery times, large yet stable volume demands, and consistency in mix of materials.  "},{"question":"\"A strategic decision, based on competition, perceived value, and brand identity.\" This describes which component of a CRM strategy?","choices":["A. Placement ","  B. Promotion ","  C. Price ","  D. Product "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Pricing is influenced by many factors other than cost of production, including competitive positions, customers' willingness to pay for the value received, and consistency with the brand identity that has been created.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about the role of purchasing in an SRM model is correct?","choices":["A. Purchasing roles have become more layered between strategic management and buying. ","  B. SRM technology has greatly complicated the tasks of purchasing managers and agents. ","  C. Under an SRM model, strategic decisions such as selection of alliance partners are pushed down to subordinate purchasing roles. ","  D. Strategic sourcing has greatly simplified the tasks associated with purchasing."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Purchasing has, in fact, become more complex with the use of strategic sourcing. Roles have become more stratified, with senior-level managers focusing on strategic decisions and lower-level managers focusing on procurement and monitoring. They are aided by SRM technology, which has automated and supported many of their new tasks, such as partner research and contracting and invoice development.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about implementing CRM technology is correct?","choices":["A. Detailed architecture design at an early stage may lead to an inflexible system that is difficult to change. ","  B. If technology is optimal, job responsibilities may remain static in the new system. ","  C. Implementation teams should represent technological areas only. ","  D. Systems should be measured against whether they increase efficiency and meet customer expectations. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Good CRM technology is easy to use and meets customer expectations. Successful implementation of CRM technology rests on a clear, well-thought-out architecture. Rather than inhibiting change, good design enhances integration and lessens the chances of conflicts as the system evolves. Since it may involve redefining jobs, implementation teams should be cross-functional.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a benefit associated with customer segmentation?","choices":["A. Better ROI on promotion budgets ","  B. Shorter sales cycle ","  C. Lower production costs ","  D. Shorter time-to-market "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Customer segmentation allows businesses to learn customer desires and habits and design more effective promotional programs. "},{"question":"In the Pareto principle, a significant percentage of a company's revenue or profits is derived from","choices":["A. less than 10 percent of the customer base. ","  B. about or less than 20 percent of the customer base. ","  C. about or less than 40 percent of the customer base. ","  D. about or less than 80 percent of the customer base"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The Pareto principle posits that a small percentage of the customer base (usually about or less than 20 percent) accounts for a large proportion of a company's revenue or profit (80 percent or more).   "},{"question":"Supply chain participant priorities often conflict. Which of the following groups sets a priority on short order lead times and quick delivery turnaround time?","choices":["A. Retailers ","  B. Suppliers ","  C. Manufacturers ","  D. Warehousers "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Retailers need short order lead times and quick delivery turnaround times "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about ISO certification is correct?","choices":["A. ISO certification may be one criterion a supplier must meet in a larger certification process. ","  B. ISO certification is a one-time process. ","  C. Because of their depth, ISO standards can often be used in place of a company's own supplier criteria in the supplier certification process. ","  D. ISO certification has limited recognition globally."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"ISO certification is a globally recognized process that certifying companies must update every three years. Since it is industry- rather than business-specific, it often complements a business's own certification process. ISO certification may be a requirement for suppliers, but because of the certification's broad criteria it is usually not the only requirement in the certification process.  "},{"question":"An organization whose IT and operations groups are able to collaborate easily is best described as","choices":["A. cross-functional. ","  B. farseeing. ","  C. able to lead. ","  D. change-oriented"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A cross-functional organization is one that enjoys cooperation between internal groups, especially IT and operations.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about virtual organizations is correct?","choices":["A. Member organizations retain their original, distinctive cultures and values. ","  B. Individual organizations must preserve their own identity and integrity. ","  C. Information belonging to member organizations remains proprietary. ","  D. Customers perceive the member organizations as distinct entities. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"In a virtual organization, there is integration of many systems and extensive sharing of information, often proprietary information. Forming virtual organizations thus requires trust and a cultural shift that embraces the common identity of the virtual organization. At the same time, the member organizations must evaluate the risk of the relationship and preserve their own identity and integrity.  "},{"question":"A business finds that a dissatisfied customer has created a Web site on which the business and its products are harshly criticized. This situation most likely represents a failure in","choices":["A. managing media for customer communication. ","  B. development of brand identity. ","  C. monitoring of competitive activities. ","  D. none of the above. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Generally, customers who resort to this tactic feel that they have not been heard by the \"offending\" business and that attempts have not been made to address their problems. This is a failure of customer communication and customer care rather than brand identity, specific communication media, or competitors' activities.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about purchased customer data is true?","choices":["A. They paint a picture of a business's own customers. ","  B. They can be very broad. ","  C. They may be more useful in new customer acquisition. ","  D. They are very useful in managing relationships with existing customers. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Data purchased from companies such as database marketing companies provide information about customers outside a company's own customer base. These data are useful in reaching new customers.  "},{"question":"How does supply chain integration help resolve the conflict between reduced cost and improved customer service?","choices":["A. By enabling direct shipping from warehouse to customer's home ","  B. By enabling delayed differentiation ","  C. By supporting factory-distributor-retailer-customer distribution pathways ","  D. By combining shipments through cross-docking "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Direct shipping from the warehouse to the customer's home lowers costs by storing inventory at a centrally located warehouse rather than at the retail location. Customer service is improved by allowing a larger selection of inventory and providing front-door delivery service.  "},{"question":"Repeated transactions are funneled through an account manager and regulated through medium-term contracts. This best exemplifies which of the following types of business relationships?","choices":["A. Collaborations/strategic alliance ","  B. Mergers and acquisitions ","  C. Ongoing relationship ","  D. Buy the market "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"An ongoing relationship involves repeated transactions, perhaps regulated through medium-term contracts. Communication is funneled through an account manager, who adjusts in all interactions to the customer's culture and way of doing business.  "},{"question":"SRM increases the visibility of the entire supply chain. This benefits SRM participants in which of the following ways?","choices":["A. Simplifies market segmentation ","  B. Enables faster response and better contingency planning ","  C. Lowers the number of required distributors ","  D. Reduces customer service calls"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Increased supply chain visibility can lessen the bullwhip effect and enable early problem detection, faster response and better contingency planning, and stronger relationships because of increased trust.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is an example of a sales force automation tool?","choices":["A. Universal queue ","  B. Tracking applications for evolving sales opportunities ","  C. Promotional program analytics ","  D. Service cyber agents "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"SFA tools assist sales representatives in various tasks from organizing contacts, tracking opportunities, and accessing product knowledge and details of current promotions (although not the analysis of promotion effects). Service cyber agents are an automated form of answering customer queries, and universal queue is a way of automating inbound customer contact.  "},{"question":"Which SRM technology allows information collected by one application or supply chain partner to be shared by all applications or partners?","choices":["A. Wireless communication ","  B. Web-based procurement ","  C. Satellite-based tracking of transportation assets ","  D. Data warehousing and mining applications"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"While the other options are also valuable SRM tools, data warehousing and mining allow sharing of information between applications and partners.  "},{"question":"An organization buys in response to an immediate need, sharing technical purchasing requirements rather than strategies or plans. This best exemplifies which of the following types of business relationships?","choices":["A. Buy the market ","  B. Ongoing relationship ","  C. Collaborations/strategic alliance ","  D. Mergers and acquisitions"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"\"Buy the market\" is a traditional approach to purchasing, in which organizations buy in response to immediate needs, choosing freely from among all the suppliers who can meet those needs and sharing technical purchasing requirements rather than strategies or plans.  "},{"question":"Central to implementing an SRM strategy is the use of PSAs (product and service agreements). Which of the following statements about PSAs between strategic partners is correct?","choices":["A. The PSA is not subject to standard strategic goal metrics. ","  B. PSAs should be standardized for all suppliers. ","  C. The PSA is crafted only after a carefully conducted pilot program. ","  D. The negotiated PSA must be mutually beneficial for both partners."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"A PSA between partners should be mutually beneficial. It may be customized, should precede pilot and full implementation, and should always be measured for improvement.  "},{"question":"A company manages catalog purchasing of stationery products and computer equipment for corporate headquarters. It provides invoicing to its clients by requisitioning department customers and delivers product. This best describes a","choices":["A. third-party logistics (3PL) company. ","  B. distributor integration (DI) network. ","  C. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. ","  D. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"This company is probably a third-party logistics provider, a company that performs all or part of an organization's procurement of materials and distribution.  "},{"question":"Which of the following best describes the critical difference between traditional and current supply chain management approaches?","choices":["A. The focus has shifted from human resource-based solutions to technology-driven solutions. ","  B. The focus has shifted from internal quality improvement and cost reduction to collaborative solutions up and down the supply chain. ","  C. The focus has shifted from inventory management to demand enhancement. ","  D. The focus has shifted from brick-and-mortar solutions to Web-based solutions. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"While in the past the strategic focus for many organizations was to improve their internal quality and reduce costs, the new focus is on implementing total supply chain solutions that require collaboration from partner organizations both upstream and downstream.  "},{"question":"A key difference between certification and supplier rating systems is that","choices":["A. Certification programs incorporate data from supply chain information systems. ","  B. Supplier rating systems measure performance at predefined intervals. ","  C. Supplier rating systems occur more frequently to capture ongoing performance levels. ","  D. Certification programs take steps to improve supplier performance. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Supplier rating systems take an approach similar to certification in setting supplier performance standards, measuring performance against those standards, and taking steps to improve supplier performance. However, they incorporate data from supply chain information systems and occur more frequently (sometimes in an ongoing, real-time manner) to paint a picture of ongoing performance levels.  "},{"question":"Which of the following component purchasing goals are reactive or defensive reasons for forming a strategic alliance?","choices":["A. Adding value to products ","  B. Building organizational expertise ","  C. The number of suppliers able to provide the component ","  D. Opening new markets "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"From a purely reactive stance, companies with certain types of supply situations may be able to manage risk better in a strategic alliance. Purchasers must consider strategic importance of the component, the complexity of the component-product interface, the number of component suppliers available, and the uncertainty of the supplier relationship.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a good example of a virtual organization?","choices":["A. Raw materials supplier that agrees to supply product for an upcoming production cycle ","  B. Merger of two competitors ","  C. Company that sells only services, not products ","  D. Strategic alliance of four companies to develop a new drug product and market it under the name of one of the companies "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"A virtual organization is a long-term strategic alliance of separate business entities that presents itself to third parties as a single entity.  "},{"question":"A retailer replenishes stock by ordering new goods from a manufacturer on a one-to-one replacement basis. This describes","choices":["A. a quick response inventory management model. ","  B. a continuous replenishment inventory management model. ","  C. a vendor-managed inventory model. ","  D. none of the above. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"In a quick response model, the retailer continues to order from the supplier, although the supplier may collect POS data for the purposes of planning and forecasting.  "},{"question":"A company performs transportation of both materials and finished product for a global manufacturer. To manage fluctuations in demand, they contract with service providers in geographical regions, who in turn manage contracts with individual suppliers. This best describes a","choices":["A. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. ","  B. distributor integration (DI) network. ","  C. third-party logistics (3PL) company. ","  D. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Fourth-party logistics providers are often found in global markets where they can combine the resources of suppliers and often 3PLs to meet the challenges of time zone, geographical, and cultural differences.  "},{"question":"Which of the following benefits applies to lifetime customers?","choices":["A. They increase the need for CRM activities. ","  B. They increase total marketing costs. ","  C. They are more difficult to satisfy than first-time or short-term customers. ","  D. They tend to have a null effect on revenue but a positive effect on profit."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Lifetime customers increase the need for CRM, but they also make it a little easier as the business learns more about them over time. Total marketing costs decline, satisfaction increases with better customer understanding, and both revenue and profit increase.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about strategic alliances is true?","choices":["A. Alliance relationships are marked by organizational integration at a few critical points. ","  B. Alliances are relationships between two or more partners in the supply chain. ","  C. In alliance relationships, flexibility is not a good thing. Processes must be rigidly followed and enforced. ","  D. Despite potential benefits, there has been little growth in the development of strategic alliances"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Alliance relationships are marked by organization integration at many points in the partners' organizations, from information systems through marketing and sales to finance.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is an example of a loyalty program?","choices":["A. \"Buy one, get two\" offer ","  B. Introductory rates ","  C. Free shipping for high-volume customers ","  D. Customer profiling system "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A loyalty program simultaneously rewards repeat or high-value customers and encourages continued business through special incentives.  "},{"question":"A business gathers information from its accounts information system to identify those customers who have bought a large volume of items in the innovative product group. This is an example of","choices":["A. setting a channel strategy. ","  B. developing a PSA. ","  C. data warehousing. ","  D. data mining."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Data mining is the process of studying data to search for previously unknown relationships.  "},{"question":"Suppliers are folded into the purchasing entity, business goals are shared, and competition has been eliminated. This best exemplifies which of the following types of business relationships?","choices":["A. Ongoing relationship ","  B. Buy the market ","  C. Mergers and acquisitions ","  D. Collaborations/strategic alliance "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"In mergers and acquisitions, suppliers are folded into the purchasing entity. Business goals are shared; business areas participate in setting strategy and planning integration of capabilities, processes, and information. Competition has been eliminated.  "},{"question":"Which of the following activities would not be useful when implementing an SRM strategy?","choices":["A. Performing a Pareto analysis of all suppliers ","  B. Developing a PSA to define deliverables ","  C. Delaying training and corporate communication of the strategy until after pilot program results are identified ","  D. Conducting a pilot study "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"All those affected by the SRM strategy should be informed and trained before the program is piloted.  "},{"question":"Grouping customers according to distinct values or needs refers to the tactic of","choices":["A. customer segment mapping. ","  B. demographic analysis. ","  C. market prioritization. ","  D. predictive analysis"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Customer segment mapping is a key component of implementing CRM strategy since it leads to a better understanding of customer values and needs and increased potential for success in responding to those values and needs.  "},{"question":"An effective customer service management strategy includes which of the following?","choices":["A. Developing a general system but allowing flexibility to customer service personnel to develop specific procedures ","  B. Restricting customer interactions to a limited set of defined scenarios that may be performed within the existing infrastructure ","  C. Delivering consistent and identical customer service to all customer segments ","  D. Development of a product and service agreement (PSA) "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Development of the PSA, procedures to handle all customer interactions, infrastructure (people and information) to perform the procedures, and metrics to measure success are all parts of a successful customer service management strategy. Customer interaction scenarios are determined by customer needs, not by existing infrastructure. Specific responses should be developed and followed. Service levels may be customized for different customer segments.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is part of the definition of SRM?","choices":["A. Tool to align the customer voice with the product produced ","  B. Philosophy applied equally to all suppliers ","  C. Way to ensure mutual profitability while meeting marketplace needs ","  D. Provides fuller communication without actual integration "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"SRM focuses on the supply side of the supply chain to ensure that customer demands can be met with a high degree of satisfaction but also with mutual profitability for all suppliers. Relationships using SRM are marked by a high degree of integration of processes and even information systems. SRM may not be appropriate in relationships with all suppliers but rather with suppliers considered key partners in maintaining the supply chain.  "},{"question":"Which of the following supply chain participants is likely to resist SCM efforts initially because they feel that they can't trust any of their supply chain partners enough to share valuable data?","choices":["A. Internal ","  B. Customer ","  C. Distributor ","  D. Supplier "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Organizations' internal members are sometimes hesitant initially to trust any of their supply chain partners enough to share what they value as important internal information or data. While most organizations are open to receiving information regarding best practices from partner organizations, they are typically not willing to reciprocate by sharing equal information.  "},{"question":"In the supply chain model, CRM is instrumental in","choices":["A. aligning distributors with retailers. ","  B. eliminating volatility in orders of raw materials. ","  C. creating and maintaining demand. ","  D. ensuring supply at the retail level."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"In general, CRM benefits the supply chain by creating and maintaining demand for products and services.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about outsourcing CRM is true?","choices":["A. CRM vendors may provide seamless customer service. ","  B. The only good reason for outsourcing CRM is cost savings. ","  C. CRM should not be outsourced. ","  D. Separation of CRM vendors should be strictly enforced to protect the outsourcing business's autonomy."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"If CRM vendors train their employees in the client's business and products and if they have adequate resources, they can convey the impression of seamless customer service. CRM may be outsourced for various reasons. Cost is not the only consideration; vendors may offer advanced capabilities, for example. Information gained by one vendor should be shared with all vendors to create a learning organization.  "},{"question":"A vulnerable customer is one who","choices":["A. has bought product that is becoming obsolete. ","  B. is about to discontinue service or stop purchasing the brand products. ","  C. the competition has been selling intensively. ","  D. is segmented into a low-value group and offered little incentive. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The most accurate answer is that a vulnerable customer is one who is about to stop being a customer. This may be due to factors described in some of the incorrect choices. A vulnerable customer may perceive little value in the relationship, may have developed little loyalty, and may be willing to try a competitor. A customer with obsolete product who does not receive customer care may soon become vulnerable.  "},{"question":"The five best practices for supply chains include which of the following?","choices":["A. Advertising and sales analysis ","  B. Outsourcing operations and logistics ","  C. Maximizing profits ","  D. Strategic sourcing and supplier management "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The five best practices for supply chains are strategic sourcing and supplier management, operations and logistics, customer relationship management and channels, information technology, and change management.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about the certification process is correct?","choices":["A. Criteria should be adjusted to individual suppliers' capabilities. ","  B. Suppliers should be clearly informed of criteria and processes to be used in the certification process. ","  C. All potential suppliers should go through the certification process. ","  D. Certification is a supplier selection tool only. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"To achieve certification's highest potential, companies must clearly communicate what they will be measuring and how. Criteria should be consistent from one supplier to the next. The outcome can be used not only for selection but also for supplier improvement. Companies usually opt to pursue the certification process only with actual or key suppliers.   "},{"question":"In the CRM business model, strategic pricing","choices":["A. is calculated by a sliding scale based upon customers' ability to pay. ","  B. must be continually analyzed to ensure that it is attractive to customers but still profitable to the business. ","  C. must be consistent across targeted customer segments. ","  D. is calculated by adding a competitive profit margin to the total costs of creation, sales, and overhead."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Pricing is generally a strategic decision, based on competition, perceived value, and brand identity. Strategic pricing must be carefully and frequently analyzed to ensure that the pricing structure is attractive to customers but still profitable to the business.   "},{"question":"Which of the following best defines a virtual organization?","choices":["A. Short-term tactical alliance in which partnering companies remain distinct and visible to end users ","  B. Merger of separate entities with common business values and goals to gain better market position ","  C. Potentially long-term relationship between separate business entities to design, produce, and distribute a product ","  D. Separate entities that collaborate to design and sell intangible products and services "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A virtual organization is best described as a short-term alliance of independent businesses for a potentially long-term relationship. Businesses cooperate to design, create, and distribute product (including services) based on shared values and are perceived by third parties as a single entity.  . "},{"question":"Cost-effective and efficient collaboration between supply chain partners requires","choices":["A. defining an early point at which to dissolve a troubled relationship. ","  B. structuring communication and decision making so that conflicts do not occur. ","  C. a conflict resolution model. ","  D. maintaining separate decision-making structures to avoid conflicts. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Forging supplier relationships represents an investment that must be protected by developing ways to identify potential and actual conflicts, resolve them without endangering the relationship, and learning from the conflict.  "},{"question":"A group of supply chain partners share information about production and delivery schedules and available transportation assets to accomplish greater efficiencies. This best describes a","choices":["A. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network. ","  B. third-party logistics (3PL) company. ","  C. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. ","  D. distributor integration (DI) network."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A collaborative transportation network allows trading partners to share their transportation assets through aligning transportation needs with assets in real time.  "},{"question":"An example of a proactive benefit driving a strategic alliance would be a concern about","choices":["A. complexity of the component's interface with the final product. ","  B. improving time to market or increasing quality. ","  C. a sourcing relationship's potential to jeopardize attaining business objectives. ","  D. strategic importance of the component being purchased. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Proactive reasons an organization should consider a strategic alliance are the alliance's ability to add value to products, enable strategic growth, increase market access, strengthen operations, increase organizational expertise, build organizational skills, and enhance financial strength.  "},{"question":"The best definition of the phrase \"contact channel strategy\" is","choices":["A. choosing media for advertising. ","  B. selection of key distributors of service or product. ","  C. designing a two-way communication architecture between customers and businesses. ","  D. none of the above."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Contact channel strategy may include the choice of advertising media and designing a distribution system, but it includes more concerns and is more interactive than those choices suggest. The contact channel strategy should address both contacting customers and being contacted by customers.  . "},{"question":"Which of the following companies is most likely to be interested in CRM?","choices":["A. Company that develops billing application software for a health-care provider ","  B. Company that manufactures testing equipment for a laboratory builder ","  C. Company that fabricates fiberglass insulation for a heating equipment manufacturer ","  D. Manufacturer of power tools"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Companies that can benefit from knowing more about the end customer or shaping the needs and wants of the end customer will be most interested in CRM. The manufacturer of power tools must design, manufacture, and sell tools that appeal to customers. The other companies are suppliers that must satisfy a purchaser's technical qualifications or expectations.  "},{"question":"Supply chain integration allows the reduction of safety stock levels, which benefits participants by","choices":["A. improving the ability to anticipate needs and convey benefits. ","  B. shortening cycle times.    ","  C. lowering inventory levels and reducing costs. ","  D. enhancing demand."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"With shorter lead and cycle times, the level of safety stock may be reduced, which leads to savings by reducing inventory levels and obsolescence costs.  "},{"question":"SRM structures and supports relationships with suppliers, thereby assisting in which of the following?","choices":["A. Focusing on cost of materials and components ","  B. Improving depth of purchased parts knowledge ","  C. Targeting suppliers for cross-selling and up-selling opportunities ","  D. Reducing procurement and excess inventory costs "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"SRM is a methodology to structure and support relationships with suppliers that will assist in reducing procurement and excess inventory costs, supporting a customer-focused business that delivers product/service customization and quality in the desired time frame, and improving processes in an ongoing manner.  "},{"question":"An example of a supplier performance reporting mechanism is","choices":["A. a certification document. ","  B. a rejected materials rate. ","  C. an automated performance alert. ","  D. a floor failure event rate."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Rates, such as number of floor failures, rejected materials, or delays in shipment, are used to compile reports of supplier performance but are not themselves reports. Reporting mechanisms include such tools as scorecards, performance failure alerts (which are online and in real time), and surveys. A certification indicates that a supplier has met criteria but does not report ongoing performance.  "},{"question":"A business is attempting to create more powerful bonds between its customers and itself by delivering greater customer satisfaction and mutual dependence. This business is pursing a strategy of","choices":["A. niche marketing. ","  B. creating lifetime customers. ","  C. competitive differentiation. ","  D. customer segmentation."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"While businesses may employ customer segmentation, competitive differentiation, and niche marketing to appeal to customers, this strategy describes the creation of lifetime customers.  "},{"question":"The cost considerations that SCM partner organizations must examine include all of the following except","choices":["A. How profitable are each of the partner SCM organizations? ","  B. What are the hardware expenses? ","  C. Are there consulting fees involved? ","  D. What are the overhead expenses?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Cost considerations that SCM partner organizations must examine include costs of hardware, software, overhead, and consulting fees.  "},{"question":"How does supply chain integration help resolve the conflict between inventory storage costs and transportation costs?","choices":["A. By reducing lead times ","  B. By enabling direct warehouse-to-customer shipping ","  C. By enabling delayed differentiation ","  D. By combining shipments through cross-docking"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Retailers may also choose to combine shipments from different manufacturers in a process called cross-docking. Decision support systems enable the supply chain to find a suitable balance between transportation and delivery costs by considering all aspects of the supply chain.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about customer segmentation is true?","choices":["A. Customer segmentation does not apply well to business (B2B) customers. ","  B. Demographic segmentation is not based on data about actual customer buying behaviors. ","  C. Customer segmentation may help increase revenue but is not a tool for increasing profitability. ","  D. Customer segmentation is a concept introduced in CRM. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Customer segmentation predates CRM but in the past relied heavily on demographic segmentation, which does not use actual customer buying behavior as CRM segmentation methods do. Customer segmentation can increase both revenue and profitability for retail as well as B2B customers.   "},{"question":"Vendor-managed inventory is an example of a collaborative initiative that can benefit supply chain participants by","choices":["A. reducing costs. ","  B. lengthening intervals between restocking. ","  C. shortening production times. ","  D. enhancing demand."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"In this arrangement, the manufacturer receives better information about market demand, enabling more efficient production and better inventory management, thereby reducing costs.  "},{"question":"A customer-focused business","choices":["A. restricts communication and distribution channels to the most profitable options. ","  B. educates customers throughout the purchasing process. ","  C. focuses on customer care rather than product/service design and delivery. ","  D. gathers information about the customer but restricts its use to critical points in the supply chain. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Customer-focused businesses try to make their customers feel better educated about what they are buying before, during, and after the purchase. They promote sharing of information about the customer throughout the supply chain, appreciate the need to consider customer needs in designing as well as marketing and distributing products, and maintain communication and distribution strategies that value convenience for the customer more than profitability.  "},{"question":"You are ordering a camping tent through a call center for a recreational equipment manufacturer. The operator notes that for a little more money you could receive significantly more value in another tent model. This is an example of","choices":["A. up-selling. ","  B. cross-selling. ","  C. a win-back program. ","  D. a loyalty program."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Up-selling is a CRM tactic in which customers are offered higher-priced or more profitable items instead of the item they were originally considering. The operator in this case may be supported by a workflow that suggests specific models and links to more data in an electronic catalog or data about the customer's previous purchases that suggest a tendency toward higher-priced purchases.   "},{"question":"A supplier tracks shipments and sales and commits to ensuring that retailers have goods on hand. Retailers do not issue purchase orders. This describes","choices":["A. a quick response inventory management model. ","  B. a continuous replenishment inventory management model. ","  C. a vendor-managed inventory model. ","  D. none of the above. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"In a continuous replenishment model, suppliers are notified daily of actual sales or warehouse shipments and commit to replenishing inventory without receiving purchase orders.  "},{"question":"\"Crafting products/services to increase customer value, potential for added value, competitive differentiation, and increased profit.\" This describes which component of a CRM strategy?","choices":["A. Promotion ","  B. Placement ","  C. Price ","  D. Product "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The product component of a CRM strategy refers to all those actions taken to craft products and services that relate to customer needs, opportunities to add value in the supply chain and enhance competitive position, and still meet profit objectives. "},{"question":"Which of the following is a benefit of collaborative transportation management (CTM)?","choices":["A. Reduction of carriers' wait time for loading and unloading ","  B. Optimization of weight and volume capacity of network resources ","  C. Increase in backhaul opportunities for carriers ","  D. All of the above"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"CTMs can deliver all of these benefits by aligning transportation needs with transportation assets to eliminate inefficiencies, such as wait time, half-filled loads, or empty backhauls (\"deadheading\").   "},{"question":"Rather than choosing the least expensive component for its computers, an electronics manufacturer factors in the costs of reverse logistics. This best exemplifies which of the following distinctions between traditional purchasing and strategic sourcing?","choices":["A. Boundary-specific versus realigned work processes and workflows ","  B. Purchase price versus total cost of ownership ","  C. Limited visibility versus entire supply chain visibility ","  D. Transactional versus collaborative "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"There is a distinction between price and total cost of ownership. For example, a manufacturer of electronics may choose a component based on the lowest price, but that choice may not translate into low cost if the low-priced components are not reliable and fail early.  "},{"question":"The tasks of the interorganizational team include which of the following?","choices":["A. Determine profits the new supply chain network will generate within the targeted market. ","  B. Identify place and promotion in a strategic plan. ","  C. Create a plan for combining best practices across the network. ","  D. Designate the initiative's channel master. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"An interorganizational team conducts an assessment to analyze demand, supply, competition, and systems as well as to determine what features will set this supply chain network apart within the targeted market. The team also creates a plan for combining best practices across the network and formulates a strategic plan.  "},{"question":"Which of the following best describes what an organization's risk portfolio should do?","choices":["A. Balance risks in terms of probability, cost of occurrence, and cost of mitigation. ","  B. Identify current risk-prone partnerships that should be severed. ","  C. Eliminate risks by predicting their likely sources. ","  D. Identify those risk costs that can shifted to a partner's portfolio."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"After determining the nature and costs of potential disruptions, organizations assemble a desirable risk portfolio that balances risks in terms of probability, cost of occurrence, and cost of mitigation "},{"question":"Which of the following is part of the correct definition of customer relationship management?","choices":["A. Focused on forecasting and analysis of information ","  B. Solely a marketing philosophy ","  C. Tool to support existing and potential customer needs ","  D. Tool to manage marketing, sales, supply planning, and production scheduling "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Information gathered in the CRM process is used to support service to customers and potential customers and sales and marketing decisions, not resource and production planning.  "},{"question":"For which of the following companies would CRM probably be a priority?","choices":["A. A company with a customer base with diverse needs and interests ","  B. A company that performs purchasing for a large manufacturer from several strategic suppliers ","  C. A company that provides raw materials for an extended supply chain in which value is added at later points in the chain ","  D. A company with one large customer who specifies product/service features "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"CRM focuses on learning more about one's customers and using this knowledge to enhance product, increase customer satisfaction, and improve revenue and profit. The company with the diverse customer base can potentially benefit greatly from being able to gather and use more information about its customers.  "},{"question":"In a commodity pricing scenario","choices":["A. Goods are sold based on added value. ","  B. Businesses compete primarily on price and availability of goods. ","  C. Competition is limited. ","  D. Businesses have greater opportunities for maintaining profit margins"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"In a commodity market, goods are distinguished primarily by lowest price and greatest availability, which creates downward pressure on profit.  "},{"question":"A chief customer officer (CCO) is in charge of","choices":["A. responding to customer dissatisfaction. ","  B. assigning account managers to high-value customers. ","  C. identifying and responding to customer care opportunities. ","  D. identifying opportunities for enhancing revenue and profit through customer interactions"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A chief customer officer may supervise management of customer dissatisfaction, but the job entails more activities, including identifying customer touch points, defining and enforcing service standards, enriching the customer experience, and helping customers navigate within the organization.  "},{"question":"Suppliers are folded into the purchasing entity, business goals are shared, and competition has been eliminated. This best exemplifies which of the following types of business relationships?","choices":["A. Buy the market ","  B. Mergers and acquisitions ","  C. Ongoing relationship ","  D. Collaborations/strategic alliance "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"In mergers and acquisitions, suppliers are folded into the purchasing entity. Business goals are shared; business areas participate in setting strategy and planning integration of capabilities, processes, and information. Competition has been eliminated. "},{"question":"An external data network is","choices":["A. an outsourced CRM information management system. ","  B. a network resulting from collaboration between the information and communication systems of a company and other members of its supply chain. ","  C. an information repository for purchased customer data. ","  D. any information system outside the business from which it may have to extract customer data."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"External data networks are created through collaboration of partners in a supply chain and facilitate the exchange and analysis of information gathered at various points in the supply chain, from factory through distribution to call centers. "},{"question":"The five best practices for supply chains include which of the following?","choices":["A. Advertising and sales analysis ","  B. Strategic sourcing and supplier management ","  C. Maximizing profits ","  D. Outsourcing operations and logistics"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The five best practices for supply chains are strategic sourcing and supplier management, operations and logistics, customer relationship management and channels, information technology, and change management.  "},{"question":"In the CRM business model, strategic pricing","choices":["A. must be consistent across targeted customer segments. ","  B. must be continually analyzed to ensure that it is attractive to customers but still profitable to the business. ","  C. is calculated by adding a competitive profit margin to the total costs of creation, sales, and overhead. ","  D. is calculated by a sliding scale based upon customers' ability to pay. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Pricing is generally a strategic decision, based on competition, perceived value, and brand identity. Strategic pricing must be carefully and frequently analyzed to ensure that the pricing structure is attractive to customers but still profitable to the business.  "},{"question":"A vulnerable customer is one who","choices":["A. is about to discontinue service or stop purchasing the brand products. ","  B. is segmented into a low-value group and offered little incentive. ","  C. the competition has been selling intensively. ","  D. has bought product that is becoming obsolete"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The most accurate answer is that a vulnerable customer is one who is about to stop being a customer. This may be due to factors described in some of the incorrect choices. A vulnerable customer may perceive little value in the relationship, may have developed little loyalty, and may be willing to try a competitor. A customer with obsolete product who does not receive customer care may soon become vulnerable.   "},{"question":"How does supply chain integration help resolve the conflict between inventory storage costs and transportation costs?","choices":["A. By reducing lead times ","  B. By enabling direct warehouse-to-customer shipping ","  C. By combining shipments through cross-docking ","  D. By enabling delayed differentiation "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Retailers may also choose to combine shipments from different manufacturers in a process called cross-docking. Decision support systems enable the supply chain to find a suitable balance between transportation and delivery costs by considering all aspects of the supply chain.  "},{"question":"\"A period marked by high costs and low sales.\" This phrase best describes what phase of the product life cycle?","choices":["A. Development ","  B. Introduction ","  C. Growth ","  D. Maturity"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Because of costs associated with marketing, establishing inventory, and developing the distribution system and because a customer base has not yet been acquired, the introduction phase of the product life cycle is marked by high costs but low sales.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about effective supplier performance measurement systems is true?","choices":["A. They enable each department within an organization to define its own supplier performance measurement procedures. ","  B. They track the performance of a narrowly defined portion of the supply chain base. ","  C. They automate key supplier performance measurement activities. ","  D. Their performance measurements, reporting, and improvements should be unilaterally defined by the purchasing organization"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Effective supplier performance measurement systems track the performance of a broad portion of the supply chain base; collaborate with suppliers on performance measurements, reporting, and improvements; automate key supplier performance measurement activities; and standardize supplier performance measurement procedures across the organization.  "},{"question":"Why does market volatility create greater need for supply chain integration?","choices":["A. Integration enables a global response to demands. ","  B. Integration helps counter consumers' and competitors' increased access to information. ","  C. Integration enables demand enhancement. ","  D. Integration helps reduce conflicts of interest."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Consumers and competitors have more and faster access to information, causing market volatility. Supply chain integration provides comparable improvements in information access.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a benefit associated with customer segmentation?","choices":["A. Lower production costs ","  B. Better ROI on promotion budgets ","  C. Shorter time-to-market ","  D. Shorter sales cycle"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Customer segmentation allows businesses to learn customer desires and habits and design more effective promotional programs. "},{"question":"Which of the following best describes a customer data warehouse (CDW)?","choices":["A. Current customer profiles stored in a database ","  B. Data about customers, products, and marketplace extracted from internal and external resources ","  C. Repository of all data related to customer transactions ","  D. Purchased data on specific customer segment "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A customer data warehouse (CDW) stores data about customers, products, and market trends, consolidating it in a manner that can facilitate future analysis to spot trends and relationships.  "},{"question":"A purchaser and its suppliers form an ongoing relationship in which they all participate in improving the system. This best exemplifies which of the following distinctions between traditional purchasing and strategic sourcing?","choices":["A. Limited visibility versus entire supply chain visibility ","  B. Purchase price versus true cost ","  C. Boundary-specific versus realigned work processes and workflows ","  D. Transactional versus collaborative "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Traditional purchasing sees each purchase as a discrete transaction. Since strategic sourcing involves ongoing relationships, there is opportunity for collaboration between the purchaser and suppliers that can result in improving the profitability of the supply chain and adding value to the final product or service.  "},{"question":"Technological challenges facing supply chain integration efforts include which of the following?","choices":["A. Underpowered, overly complex, or poorly designed solutions ","  B. Inability to customize off-the-shelf solutions ","  C. Open system infrastructures ","  D. Difficulty in accessing information"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"As with any technological solution, systems may be underpowered, overly complex, poorly designed, or just not right for the job at hand. In general, more systems today are designed to be open, information is more accessible, and software solutions are more easily customized to specific settings. "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about implementing CRM technology is correct?","choices":["A. Detailed architecture design at an early stage may lead to an inflexible system that is difficult to change. ","  B. Implementation teams should represent technological areas only. ","  C. Systems should be measured against whether they increase efficiency and meet customer expectations. ","  D. If technology is optimal, job responsibilities may remain static in the new system. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Good CRM technology is easy to use and meets customer expectations. Successful implementation of CRM technology rests on a clear, well-thought-out architecture. Rather than inhibiting change, good design enhances integration and lessens the chances of conflicts as the system evolves. Since it may involve redefining jobs, implementation teams should be cross-functional.  "},{"question":"A key difference between certification and supplier rating systems is that","choices":["A. Supplier rating systems measure performance at predefined intervals. ","  B. Certification programs incorporate data from supply chain information systems. ","  C. Certification programs take steps to improve supplier performance. ","  D. Supplier rating systems occur more frequently to capture ongoing performance levels. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Supplier rating systems take an approach similar to certification in setting supplier performance standards, measuring performance against those standards, and taking steps to improve supplier performance. However, they incorporate data from supply chain information systems and occur more frequently (sometimes in an ongoing, real-time manner) to paint a picture of ongoing performance levels.  "},{"question":"A chief customer officer (CCO) is in charge of","choices":["A. responding to customer dissatisfaction. ","  B. identifying and responding to customer care opportunities. ","  C. assigning account managers to high-value customers. ","  D. identifying opportunities for enhancing revenue and profit through customer interactions."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A chief customer officer may supervise management of customer dissatisfaction, but the job entails more activities, including identifying customer touch points, defining and enforcing service standards, enriching the customer experience, and helping customers navigate within the organization.   "},{"question":"Which of the following is an example of a loyalty program?","choices":["A. Introductory rates ","  B. Free shipping for high-volume customers ","  C. \"Buy one, get two\" offer ","  D. Customer profiling system "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A loyalty program simultaneously rewards repeat or high-value customers and encourages continued business through special incentives. "},{"question":"Cost-effective and efficient collaboration between supply chain partners requires","choices":["A. structuring communication and decision making so that conflicts do not occur. ","  B. defining an early point at which to dissolve a troubled relationship. ","  C. a conflict resolution model. ","  D. maintaining separate decision-making structures to avoid conflicts. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Forging supplier relationships represents an investment that must be protected by developing ways to identify potential and actual conflicts, resolve them without endangering the relationship, and learning from the conflict.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about the role of purchasing in an SRM model is correct?","choices":["A. SRM technology has greatly complicated the tasks of purchasing managers and agents. ","  B. Strategic sourcing has greatly simplified the tasks associated with purchasing. ","  C. Purchasing roles have become more layered between strategic management and buying. ","  D. Under an SRM model, strategic decisions such as selection of alliance partners are pushed down to subordinate purchasing roles. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Purchasing has, in fact, become more complex with the use of strategic sourcing. Roles have become more stratified, with senior-level managers focusing on strategic decisions and lower-level managers focusing on procurement and monitoring. They are aided by SRM technology, which has automated and supported many of their new tasks, such as partner research and contracting and invoice development.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about virtual organizations is correct?","choices":["A. Customers perceive the member organizations as distinct entities. ","  B. Individual organizations must preserve their own identity and integrity. ","  C. Member organizations retain their original, distinctive cultures and values. ","  D. Information belonging to member organizations remains proprietary. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"In a virtual organization, there is integration of many systems and extensive sharing of information, often proprietary information. Forming virtual organizations thus requires trust and a cultural shift that embraces the common identity of the virtual organization. At the same time, the member organizations must evaluate the risk of the relationship and preserve their own identity and integrity.  "},{"question":"Which of the statements about workflow management systems is correct?","choices":["A. They are a form of automated CRM. ","  B. They ensure consistency in implementing CRM policies. ","  C. They allow access to customer information and communications at critical service points. ","  D. All of the above"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Workflow management systems automate a sequence of steps and communications that must be completed to handle a customer situation. This is especially valuable when resolving a customer's problem may involve multiple company employees. Workflow management systems allow the system users to visualize the entire relationship and share the same information about the customer at all critical service points.   "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about vendor-managed inventory is true?","choices":["A. Inventory levels can be adjusted according to different variables. ","  B. Retailers have no hand in setting initial inventory; historical data are used. ","  C. Retailers maintain oversight on ordering. ","  D. Inventory data cannot be tied to MPS or MRP. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Although vendors may suggest inventory levels, retailers must approve initial levels. After that point, levels will be maintained by the vendor according to an agreement and models based on POS and shipment data for greatest customer satisfaction and return on inventory. Data can be tied into planning processes so that MPSs can be created and MRPs set.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about strategic alliances is true?","choices":["A. In alliance relationships, flexibility is not a good thing. Processes must be rigidly followed and enforced. ","  B. Alliances are relationships between two or more partners in the supply chain. ","  C. Alliance relationships are marked by organizational integration at a few critical points. ","  D. Despite potential benefits, there has been little growth in the development of strategic alliances"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Alliance relationships are marked by organization integration at many points in the partners' organizations, from information systems through marketing and sales to finance.  "},{"question":"An organization buys in response to an immediate need, sharing technical purchasing requirements rather than strategies or plans. This best exemplifies which of the following types of business relationships?","choices":["A. Buy the market ","  B. Collaborations/strategic alliance ","  C. Mergers and acquisitions ","  D. Ongoing relationship "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"\"Buy the market\" is a traditional approach to purchasing, in which organizations buy in response to immediate needs, choosing freely from among all the suppliers who can meet those needs and sharing technical purchasing requirements rather than strategies or plans.   "},{"question":"Which of the following tasks is most likely to be performed by a purchasing agent/planner rather than a purchasing manager?","choices":["A. Negotiating contracts with strategic sourcing partners ","  B. Selecting suppliers ","  C. Analyzing value of supply process ","  D. Order placement "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Purchasing managers focus on strategic tasks such as supplier selection, contract negotiation, and analysis and evaluation of the supply system. Purchasing agents or planners focus on placing orders, following up with suppliers as needed, monitoring supply needs, and measuring supplier performance "},{"question":"In a commodity pricing scenario","choices":["A. Goods are sold based on added value. ","  B. Businesses have greater opportunities for maintaining profit margins. ","  C. Businesses compete primarily on price and availability of goods. ","  D. Competition is limited."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"In a commodity market, goods are distinguished primarily by lowest price and greatest availability, which creates downward pressure on profit.  "},{"question":"A company performs transportation of both materials and finished product for a global manufacturer. To manage fluctuations in demand, they contract with service providers in geographical regions, who in turn manage contracts with individual suppliers. This best describes a","choices":["A. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. ","  B. third-party logistics (3PL) company. ","  C. distributor integration (DI) network. ","  D. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Fourth-party logistics providers are often found in global markets where they can combine the resources of suppliers and often 3PLs to meet the challenges of time zone, geographical, and cultural differences.  "},{"question":"In an SRM environment, a framework of performance metrics should be established to","choices":["A. achieve 50 percent adherence and adaptation by all partners. ","  B. achieve annual cost reduction of 10 percent. ","  C. monitor and identify opportunities for improvement. ","  D. penalize partners who do not adhere to agreed rules. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"One of the reasons to establish metrics and then monitor performance is to identify opportunities to improve supplier performance.  "},{"question":"Supply chain participant priorities often conflict. Which of the following groups sets a priority on high production output and low production costs?","choices":["A. Retailers ","  B. Customers ","  C. Suppliers ","  D. Manufacturers"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Manufacturing organizations strive for high production output and low production costs.  "},{"question":"Supply chain integration provides which of the following?","choices":["A. Increased warehousing capacities ","  B. Lower information technology cost ","  C. Reduced forecast accuracy ","  D. Lower shortage costs "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Information sharing benefits organizations by improving forecasts, improving coordination of manufacturing and distribution systems and strategies, reducing lead times, and accelerating reactions to marketing data. Information technology costs may increase but are offset by other benefits. "},{"question":"\"Customers provide input into what they want the business to be selling.\" This activity occurs during which phase of the product life cycle?","choices":["A. Development ","  B. Introduction ","  C. Growth ","  D. Maturity"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"During the development phase of the product life cycle, CRM businesses research customer needs and expectations and incorporate this research into product design and the entire CRM strategy (i.e., price, placement, promotional message).  "},{"question":"Supply chain participant priorities often conflict. Which of the following groups sets a priority on product and feature variety and price reduction?","choices":["A. Manufacturers ","  B. Customers ","  C. Retailers ","  D. Suppliers "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Customers demand a variety of products and features as well as low prices.  "},{"question":"Which of the following capability improvement goals are proactive reasons for forming a strategic alliance?","choices":["A. Acquiring competitive high-tech equipment ","  B. Acquiring technological expertise in weaker areas of the company ","  C. Improving time to market or increasing quality ","  D. Improving management compensation programs"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Proactive reasons for an organization to consider a strategic alliance are the alliance's ability to add value to products, enable strategic growth, increase market access, strengthen operations, increase organizational expertise, build organizational skills, and enhance financial strength.  "},{"question":"A company maintains a secondary outsourced transportation network capable of meeting the needs of its primary customer base. This is an example of","choices":["A. outsourcing transportation needs. ","  B. using an off-site delivery center. ","  C. managing possible risks of SRM outsourcing. ","  D. poor outsourcing practice"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"It is reasonable to outsource transportation, especially in a global marketplace. And it is an especially sound practice to manage risks associated with this outsourcing by maintaining a redundant supplier in the event of disruptions with the primary outsourced transportation network.  "},{"question":"A business finds that a dissatisfied customer has created a Web site on which the business and its products are harshly criticized. This situation most likely represents a failure in","choices":["A. managing media for customer communication. ","  B. development of brand identity. ","  C. monitoring of competitive activities. ","  D. none of the above."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Generally, customers who resort to this tactic feel that they have not been heard by the \"offending\" business and that attempts have not been made to address their problems. This is a failure of customer communication and customer care rather than brand identity, specific communication media, or competitors' activities.  "},{"question":"A business is attempting to create more powerful bonds between its customers and itself by delivering greater customer satisfaction and mutual dependence. This business is pursing a strategy of","choices":["A. competitive differentiation. ","  B. niche marketing. ","  C. creating lifetime customers. ","  D. customer segmentation."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"While businesses may employ customer segmentation, competitive differentiation, and niche marketing to appeal to customers, this strategy describes the creation of lifetime customers.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the best example of risk mitigation in a strategic alliance?","choices":["A. Surmounting limited availability of component suppliers. ","  B. Improving overall financial position. ","  C. Overcoming barriers to market entry. ","  D. Improving operations by lowering system costs."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"From a purely reactive stance, companies with certain types of supply situations may be able to manage risk better in a strategic alliance. Purchasers must consider the strategic importance of the component, the complexity of the component-product interface, the number of component suppliers available, and the uncertainty of the supplier relationship.  "},{"question":"Which of the following best describes the critical difference between traditional and current supply chain management approaches?","choices":["A. The focus has shifted from inventory management to demand enhancement. ","  B. The focus has shifted from human resource-based solutions to technology-driven solutions. ","  C. The focus has shifted from internal quality improvement and cost reduction to collaborative solutions up and down the supply chain. ","  D. The focus has shifted from brick-and-mortar solutions to Web-based solutions."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"While in the past the strategic focus for many organizations was to improve their internal quality and reduce costs, the new focus is on implementing total supply chain solutions that require collaboration from partner organizations both upstream and downstream.  "},{"question":"A group of supply chain partners share information about production and delivery schedules and available transportation assets to accomplish greater efficiencies. This best describes a","choices":["A. third-party logistics (3PL) company. ","  B. distributor integration (DI) network. ","  C. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. ","  D. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network.  "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"A collaborative transportation network allows trading partners to share their transportation assets through aligning transportation needs with assets in real time.  "},{"question":"Inventory status, capacity status and plans, production schedules, and shipment and demand forecasts are all shared by all parties on a real-time, online basis. This best exemplifies which of the following distinctions between traditional purchasing and strategic sourcing?","choices":["A. Limited visibility versus entire supply chain visibility ","  B. Purchase price versus true cost ","  C. Transactional versus collaborative ","  D. Boundary-specific versus realigned work processes and workflows "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"When information from suppliers, manufacturers, distributors, retailers, and customers is available for analysis, there is enhanced visibility of the supply chain and opportunities for improvement. Demand information, inventory status, capacity status, capacity plans, production schedules, promotion plans, shipment forecasts, and demand forecasts are all shared and ideally can be accessed by all parties on a real-time, online basis.  "},{"question":"A company invites key business customers to participate in the performance evaluations of its account managers. This is an example of","choices":["A. measuring customer satisfaction. ","  B. supply chain integration. ","  C. voice of the customer information gathering. ","  D. collaborative management practices. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Measurement of customer satisfaction is a key element of CRM. B2B companies may measure the CRM effectiveness of their account managers by inviting the managers' customers to participate in their performance evaluations. VOC is considered a more general research tool.  "},{"question":"How does greater supply chain integration affect demand enhancement?","choices":["A. By reducing the need to retool product lines constantly ","  B. By improving the ability to anticipate needs and convey benefits ","  C. By standardizing prices across channels ","  D. By increasing the number of response channels available to consumers "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"When manufacturers and retailers collaborate by sharing information, they develop products that are better able to meet the needs of the customer and are also better able to communicate the benefits to those customers. This may actually lead to premium prices for certain types of deliveries.   . "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about technology and CRM/SRM is true?","choices":["A. Both CRM and SRM are essentially technological. ","  B. The effects of technology are more significant in SRM than CRM. ","  C. Technology plays a supporting role in CRM and SRM. ","  D. All of the above"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"While CRM and SRM are not synonymous with technical tools (they are philosophies and competitive strategies), they are both greatly supported by technological solutions.  "},{"question":"The steps for successfully implementing a strategic supplier alliance include","choices":["A. developing employee negotiation and joint problem solving skills. ","  B. avoiding conflicts throughout the relationship. ","  C. establishing a well-defined purchasing contract with potential partners. ","  D. thinking in terms of the overall goals of the channel master. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Because collaboration skills may not come naturally to everyone, firms must develop their employees' skills for resolving conflicts, negotiating, solving problems jointly, and conducting difficult conversations. Conflicts are unavoidable but must be treated as learning experiences. Agreements must be flexible. Alliance managers must focus on the overall goals of the alliance rather than those of the channel master.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about ISO certification is correct?","choices":["A. ISO certification may be one criterion a supplier must meet in a larger certification process. ","  B. ISO certification is a one-time process. ","  C. Because of their depth, ISO standards can often be used in place of a company's own supplier criteria in the supplier certification process. ","  D. ISO certification has limited recognition globally. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"ISO certification is a globally recognized process that certifying companies must update every three years. Since it is industry- rather than business-specific, it often complements a business's own certification process. ISO certification may be a requirement for suppliers, but because of the certification's broad criteria it is usually not the only requirement in the certification process.  "},{"question":"An effective customer service management strategy includes which of the following?","choices":["A. Restricting customer interactions to a limited set of defined scenarios that may be performed within the existing infrastructure ","  B. Developing a general system but allowing flexibility to customer service personnel to develop specific procedures ","  C. Delivering consistent and identical customer service to all customer segments ","  D. Development of a product and service agreement (PSA) "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Development of the PSA, procedures to handle all customer interactions, infrastructure (people and information) to perform the procedures, and metrics to measure success are all parts of a successful customer service management strategy. Customer interaction scenarios are determined by customer needs, not by existing infrastructure. Specific responses should be developed and followed. Service levels may be customized for different customer segments.  "},{"question":"Which of the following companies is most likely to be interested in CRM?","choices":["A. Company that fabricates fiberglass insulation for a heating equipment manufacturer ","  B. Manufacturer of power tools ","  C. Company that manufactures testing equipment for a laboratory builder ","  D. Company that develops billing application software for a health-care provider "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Companies that can benefit from knowing more about the end customer or shaping the needs and wants of the end customer will be most interested in CRM. The manufacturer of power tools must design, manufacture, and sell tools that appeal to customers. The other companies are suppliers that must satisfy a purchaser's technical qualifications or expectations.  "},{"question":"An example of a supplier performance reporting mechanism is","choices":["A. a certification document. ","  B. a floor failure event rate. ","  C. an automated performance alert. ","  D. a rejected materials rate."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Rates, such as number of floor failures, rejected materials, or delays in shipment, are used to compile reports of supplier performance but are not themselves reports. Reporting mechanisms include such tools as scorecards, performance failure alerts (which are online and in real time), and surveys. A certification indicates that a supplier has met criteria but does not report ongoing performance.  "},{"question":"You are ordering a camping tent through a call center for a recreational equipment manufacturer. The operator notes that for a little more money you could receive significantly more value in another tent model. This is an example of","choices":["A. a loyalty program. ","  B. cross-selling. ","  C. a win-back program. ","  D. up-selling. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Up-selling is a CRM tactic in which customers are offered higher-priced or more profitable items instead of the item they were originally considering. The operator in this case may be supported by a workflow that suggests specific models and links to more data in an electronic catalog or data about the customer's previous purchases that suggest a tendency toward higher-priced purchases.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about the challenges of implementing CRM and SRM strategies is true?","choices":["A. Managers must acquire new skill sets. ","  B. Decision making must become more centralized and uniform. ","  C. Technology is too complex and expensive. ","  D. None of the above"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"As structures and processes change, managers will need to acquire new skills to support implementation of SRM and CRM. Decision making will actually move downward throughout the organization, closer to critical points in the supply chain. Technology is increasingly available, powerful, and easy to integrate.  "},{"question":"Increased customer visibility means","choices":["A. knowing what each customer values. ","  B. being aware of each point of contact between the customer and the business. ","  C. seeing the transaction from the customer's viewpoint. ","  D. all of the above. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Increased customer visibility is a benefit of CRM in that CRM helps businesses to see each point of the purchasing transaction from the customer's perspective and to understand what the customer needs and values.  "},{"question":"\"A technological advance that has led to both greater global competition and collaboration.\" This might best describe","choices":["A. advanced telephony features. ","  B. the intranet. ","  C. the computer. ","  D. the Internet."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"While the computer, intranets, and advanced telephony have certainly enhanced both supplier and customer relationship management, the Internet has made the largest impact on communication with customers and between partners in the supply chain.  "},{"question":"Which of the following component purchasing goals are reactive or defensive reasons for forming a strategic alliance?","choices":["A. Adding value to products ","  B. Building organizational expertise ","  C. The number of suppliers able to provide the component ","  D. Opening new markets"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"From a purely reactive stance, companies with certain types of supply situations may be able to manage risk better in a strategic alliance. Purchasers must consider strategic importance of the component, the complexity of the component-product interface, the number of component suppliers available, and the uncertainty of the supplier relationship.  "},{"question":"Central to implementing an SRM strategy is the use of PSAs (product and service agreements). Which of the following statements about PSAs between strategic partners is correct?","choices":["A. The PSA is not subject to standard strategic goal metrics. ","  B. The negotiated PSA must be mutually beneficial for both partners. ","  C. The PSA is crafted only after a carefully conducted pilot program. ","  D. PSAs should be standardized for all suppliers. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A PSA between partners should be mutually beneficial. It may be customized, should precede pilot and full implementation, and should always be measured for improvement.   "},{"question":"Which one of the following is required for successful implementation of CRM and/or SRM strategies?","choices":["A. A new workforce ","  B. New job definitions ","  C. Greater emphasis on task-focused responsibility centers ","  D. Greater control from the top down"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Organizations implementing CRM and SRM must move toward greater collaboration and away from more hierarchical structures defined by task-focused responsibility centers and top-down decision making. They call for a new attitude and new skills in the existing workforce.  "},{"question":"SRM structures and supports relationships with suppliers, thereby assisting in which of the following?","choices":["A. Improving depth of purchased parts knowledge ","  B. Reducing procurement and excess inventory costs ","  C. Focusing on cost of materials and components ","  D. Targeting suppliers for cross-selling and up-selling opportunities"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"SRM is a methodology to structure and support relationships with suppliers that will assist in reducing procurement and excess inventory costs, supporting a customer-focused business that delivers product/service customization and quality in the desired time frame, and improving processes in an ongoing manner.  "},{"question":"\"The design and implementation of two-way communication between a business and its customers.\" This describes which component of a CRM strategy?","choices":["A. Promotion ","  B. Placement ","  C. Product ","  D. Price"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The traditional marketing definition of placement has been expanded to include not only getting product into the hands of customers (distribution) but also the customer's ability to access the business (e.g., for information, actual sales, or support).  "},{"question":"\"Customer interest is high, and supply must be managed to meet demand and avoid stockouts that could boost growing competition.\" This sentence best describes what phase of the product life cycle?","choices":["A. Development ","  B. Introduction ","  C. Growth ","  D. Maturity"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"During the growth phase, the customer base increases and competitors begin to enter the market. Data on the growing customer base must be analyzed for new opportunities, and supply must be managed to meet growing demand.  "},{"question":"In a customer-focused organization, the starting point for new product development is","choices":["A. evaluating current customer product complaints. ","  B. identifying customer need. ","  C. identifying a new market niche. ","  D. identifying a price point most acceptable to lifetime customers. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"In a customer-focused world, the starting point for a product is often customer need.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the key to enabling supply chains to more quickly respond to customer demand and increase participants' profitability?","choices":["A. Creating an alliance with a key supplier ","  B. Information sharing with key partners ","  C. Creating individual partnerships ","  D. Collaborative planning across the entire supply chain "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The key is collaborative planning across the supply chain rather than mere information sharing or single alliances.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about the role of SRM in the supply chain model is correct?","choices":["A. It measures success only by satisfaction of end customers. ","  B. It focuses on gaining information about customers. ","  C. It focuses on meeting demand. ","  D. It helps ensure the same profitability for all supply chain elements"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"SRM helps ensure that demand created by CRM can be fulfilled in a manner profitable for all supply chain partners while maintaining customer satisfaction. Success of supplier relationships may be measured by various means, including time-to-market, cost efficiency, competitive advantage, and end customer satisfaction. "},{"question":"Which of the following companies is most likely to be interested in SRM?","choices":["A. Company that produces video games ","  B. Company that performs market research for political candidates ","  C. Credit card company ","  D. Paint manufacturer that purchases chemicals and dyes from various suppliers "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Companies whose ability to meet customer demands rests on their control over the supply side of the supply chain model will be most interested in SRM. The other companies are primarily concerned with understanding and responding to customer needs and expectations.  "},{"question":"Lifetime customers","choices":["A. have forged a win-win relationship with the business in question. ","  B. are increasingly more expensive for a business to maintain as they become more demanding. ","  C. are common in commodity markets driven by price rather than value. ","  D. can increase revenue but have a neutral effect on profit."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Lifetime customers have a win-win relationship with the businesses they frequent. The customers gain greater satisfaction while the business enjoys decreased marketing costs and increased revenue and profit potential. Lifetime customers are not common in markets competing on price rather than added value.  "},{"question":"The best definition of the phrase \"contact channel strategy\" is","choices":["A. choosing media for advertising. ","  B. selection of key distributors of service or product. ","  C. designing a two-way communication architecture between customers and businesses. ","  D. none of the above."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Contact channel strategy may include the choice of advertising media and designing a distribution system, but it includes more concerns and is more interactive than those choices suggest. The contact channel strategy should address both contacting customers and being contacted by customers.  "},{"question":"Maintaining a high level of customer care is critical to CRM brand image promotion, because","choices":["A. Brand image awareness has become independent of product satisfaction. ","  B. Price and placement are no longer of importance to today's service-conscious customer. ","  C. Customer loyalty no longer extends from an individual product to the supplier of that product. ","  D. The Internet has given dissatisfied customers the means to make their disloyalty quickly and widely known. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Dissatisfied customers have the means to make their disloyalty very well-known by the Internet. Complaints posted on Web sites, Web logs, chat rooms, or electronic bulletin boards can have a significant impact on today's Internet-savvy customer and can destroy a once-strong business relationship.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about CRM strategy components is true?","choices":["A. The starting point for product design is the customer. ","  B. Promotion in CRM is distinctly different from traditional marketing strategies. ","  C. Price is determined primarily by the cost of production. ","  D. Placement is determined primarily by product specifications. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Successful product designs begin with knowledge of the customer's needs and buying habits. Promotional activities are greatly supported and enhanced by CRM abilities, but promotion decisions, goals, and activities are, for the most part, unchanged from the traditional marketing model. Price may be determined by a number of factors, as may placement.  "},{"question":"A customer-focused business","choices":["A. focuses on customer care rather than product/service design and delivery. ","  B. educates customers throughout the purchasing process. ","  C. restricts communication and distribution channels to the most profitable options. ","  D. gathers information about the customer but restricts its use to critical points in the supply chain"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Customer-focused businesses try to make their customers feel better educated about what they are buying before, during, and after the purchase. They promote sharing of information about the customer throughout the supply chain, appreciate the need to consider customer needs in designing as well as marketing and distributing products, and maintain communication and distribution strategies that value convenience for the customer more than profitability.  "},{"question":"In which type of customer segmentation are customers grouped by income?","choices":["A. Segmentation by demographics ","  B. Segmentation by need ","  C. Segmentation by channel ","  D. Segmentation by value "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Demographic segmentation groups customers by group characteristics such as age, income, marital status, or family size.  "},{"question":"How does supply chain integration help resolve the conflict between greater product variety and reduced inventory demand?","choices":["A. By reducing lead times ","  B. By combining shipments through cross-docking ","  C. By enabling direct warehouse-to-customer shipping ","  D. By enabling delayed differentiation "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Shipping generic products and creating the customer variations further down the supply chain (delayed differentiation) aggregates customer demand across all products. This produces a more accurate demand forecast with a smaller degree of variability, allowing reduced storage of safety stock.  "},{"question":"What is the correct term for a CRM tactic described as \"an analytical model to identify vulnerable customers\"?","choices":["A. Data mining ","  B. Predictive churn ","  C. Loyalty programs ","  D. Win-back programs "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Predictive churn uses data about individual customer transactions and histories to identify trends that indicate that a customer may switch to a competitor or cease being a customer. As a result, the vulnerable customer may be offered incentives, such as loyalty programs. The data used in the model may be gathered through data mining.  "},{"question":"In an SCM implementation effort, the channel master is","choices":["A. the organization that drives the implementation process. ","  B. the person designated as strategic team leader. ","  C. the organization that designates the optimal delivery channels. ","  D. the person who designates the optimal communications channels."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Designating one organization as channel master positioned at the center of the initiative during its inception can contribute to the strategy's success. The channel master should be capable of rallying supporters and driving the implementation beyond the preoccupation with improving internal competencies.  "},{"question":"Which of the following best describes what an organization's risk portfolio should do?","choices":["A. Identify those risk costs that can shifted to a partner's portfolio. ","  B. Balance risks in terms of probability, cost of occurrence, and cost of mitigation. ","  C. Identify current risk-prone partnerships that should be severed. ","  D. Eliminate risks by predicting their likely sources. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"After determining the nature and costs of potential disruptions, organizations assemble a desirable risk portfolio that balances risks in terms of probability, cost of occurrence, and cost of mitigation.  "},{"question":"Which of the following factors has led to greater customer focus in business?","choices":["A. Higher quality of goods and services ","  B. Advances in technology ","  C. Greater global competition ","  D. All of the above"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"All of the answers are correct. Higher quality, made possible through technology, has created increased customer expectations, which has in turn led to price as a differentiating factor. This has created a downward pressure on profit margin. Greater customer focus helps counter this pressure.  "},{"question":"Which of the following SRM activities might be outsourced successfully?","choices":["A. Setting of procurement budgets ","  B. Selection of strategic partners ","  C. Setting corporate goals and developing strategy for alliances ","  D. Contracting with strategic partners  "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Many SRM tasks may be outsourced, from researching and contracting with alliance partners to development of technology. However, companies should never outsource strategic tasks or core competencies.  "},{"question":"\"The most profitable period but also the period most vulnerable to competitive inroads.\" This phrase best describes what phase of the product life cycle?","choices":["A. Development ","  B. Introduction ","  C. Growth ","  D. Maturity"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"During the maturity phase of the product life cycle, the costs of acquiring sales are declining, so profit is higher. At the same time, growing competition places pressure on prices. Increased sales promotion and aggressive customer acquisition help balance this influence.  "},{"question":"In a supply chain, distributors can refer customers to other distributors who have needed product on hand. This best describes a","choices":["A. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. ","  B. distributor integration (DI) network. ","  C. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network. ","  D. third-party logistics (3PL) company. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Using modern information and communication systems, distributor integration relationships allow distributors to share access to product and service.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about outsourcing CRM is true?","choices":["A. The only good reason for outsourcing CRM is cost savings. ","  B. CRM should not be outsourced. ","  C. CRM vendors may provide seamless customer service. ","  D. Separation of CRM vendors should be strictly enforced to protect the outsourcing business's autonomy. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"If CRM vendors train their employees in the client's business and products and if they have adequate resources, they can convey the impression of seamless customer service. CRM may be outsourced for various reasons. Cost is not the only consideration; vendors may offer advanced capabilities, for example. Information gained by one vendor should be shared with all vendors to create a learning organization.   "},{"question":"A company manages catalog purchasing of stationery products and computer equipment for corporate headquarters. It provides invoicing to its clients by requisitioning department customers and delivers product. This best describes a","choices":["A. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network. ","  B. third-party logistics (3PL) company. ","  C. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. ","  D. distributor integration (DI) network. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"This company is probably a third-party logistics provider, a company that performs all or part of an organization's procurement of materials and distribution.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about a customer data warehouse (CDW) is correct?","choices":["A. One-to-one marketing cannot be achieved without using a CDW. ","  B. CDWs are primarily used as measurement tools. ","  C. CDWs are maintained as separate entities from a company's customer databases. ","  D. None of the above"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Because it allows a high degree of customization, one-to-one marketing programs cannot be implemented without using a CDW. CDWs are used for a variety of purposes, including segmentation, implementing different offers to customers, analyzing buying behaviors to detect preferences, and supporting strategic decisions, such as the allocation of human resources. They are usually used in conjunction with information from a company's other databases.  "},{"question":"Which of the following supply chain participants is likely to resist SCM efforts because they feel that e-marketplaces have the effect of reducing their products and services to a commodity?","choices":["A. Supplier ","  B. Distributor ","  C. Customer ","  D. Internal "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Many suppliers feel that e-marketplaces have the effect of reducing their products and services to a commodity where price is emphasized rather than quality or the partnership.  "},{"question":"Creation of brand image is a concern related to","choices":["A. placement. ","  B. product. ","  C. promotion. ","  D. pricing. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Pricing, product, and placement are all important strategy elements in implementing and maintaining brand image or identity, but creation of the desired image is a promotional activity.  "},{"question":"Which of the following factors has led to strategic sourcing and greater integration in the supply chain?","choices":["A. Greater fragmentation on both sides of the supply chain ","  B. Shrinking global markets ","  C. Decreasing customer response time ","  D. Commodity pricing"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Commodity pricing has made it more important for businesses to streamline the supply chain and become more cost-effective. The supply chain has, in fact, consolidated rather than fragmented; global markets have grown rather than shrunk. Consolidation may necessitate strategic sourcing as the number of sources narrows. Growing global markets present opportunities but also costs and risks that must be managed.  "},{"question":"SRM has been used in the parts/after-market industry to","choices":["A. retool aging technology. ","  B. select suppliers. ","  C. gather information about customers. ","  D. implement both production and sales tactics. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"SRM has been used in the parts or after-market industry to plan both strategy and tactics as well as to budget and manage specific business events, such as managing inventory.  "},{"question":"Grouping customers according to distinct values or needs refers to the tactic of","choices":["A. predictive analysis. ","  B. customer segment mapping. ","  C. market prioritization. ","  D. demographic analysis. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Customer segment mapping is a key component of implementing CRM strategy since it leads to a better understanding of customer values and needs and increased potential for success in responding to those values and needs.  "},{"question":"Supply chain participant priorities often conflict. Which of the following groups sets a priority on flexible delivery times, large volumes, and consistent materials mixes?","choices":["A. Logistics managers ","  B. Suppliers ","  C. Warehouse managers ","  D. Retailers"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Suppliers of raw materials typically prefer flexible delivery times, large yet stable volume demands, and consistency in mix of materials.  "},{"question":"How does supply chain integration help resolve the conflict between reduced cost and improved customer service?","choices":["A. By supporting factory-distributor-retailer-customer distribution pathways ","  B. By enabling delayed differentiation ","  C. By combining shipments through cross-docking ","  D. By enabling direct shipping from warehouse to customer's home "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Direct shipping from the warehouse to the customer's home lowers costs by storing inventory at a centrally located warehouse rather than at the retail location. Customer service is improved by allowing a larger selection of inventory and providing front-door delivery service.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about purchased customer data is true?","choices":["A. They may be more useful in new customer acquisition. ","  B. They paint a picture of a business's own customers. ","  C. They are very useful in managing relationships with existing customers. ","  D. They can be very broad. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Data purchased from companies such as database marketing companies provide information about customers outside a company's own customer base. These data are useful in reaching new customers.  "},{"question":"Which one of these companies is practicing good SRM risk management?","choices":["A. This company relies on the selection process as its only means of risk management. ","  B. This company develops detailed plans to shift work orders among several certified global suppliers in the event of labor disruptions in their countries. ","  C. This company requires in its contracts that all suppliers use a defined third-party transportation provider for all shipments. ","  D. This company sources a key raw material from one supplier who reliably provides the lowest price.  "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Single sourcing of a key material or component is not a good example of risk management, even if the supplier is the lowest-cost provider. Good risk management may involve additional costs incurred through maintaining redundancy in the supply chain and requiring additional supplier performance or assumption of risk.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is part of the definition of SRM?","choices":["A. Provides fuller communication without actual integration ","  B. Philosophy applied equally to all suppliers ","  C. Tool to align the customer voice with the product produced ","  D. Way to ensure mutual profitability while meeting marketplace needs"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"SRM focuses on the supply side of the supply chain to ensure that customer demands can be met with a high degree of satisfaction but also with mutual profitability for all suppliers. Relationships using SRM are marked by a high degree of integration of processes and even information systems. SRM may not be appropriate in relationships with all suppliers but rather with suppliers considered key partners in maintaining the supply chain.  "},{"question":"Which of the following are current global forces shaping supply chain management strategies?","choices":["A. Greater market volatility ","  B. Shrinking markets ","  C. Increased difficulties in communication and application sharing ","  D. Increased influence of trade unions "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Companies are responding to the forces of globalization, increased project complexity, and greater market volatility by investing in technology that will enable them to better manage knowledge both within and across organizations.  "},{"question":"After selecting the proper partner, the next step in creating a successful alliance is to","choices":["A. appoint an alliance manager. ","  B. establish ground rules. ","  C. negotiate a win-win deal. ","  D. engage in a collaborative corporate mindset."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Before the rules, supervision, and improvement of the relationship can be pursued, a win-win deal must be negotiated. This sets the tone for the future alliance.  "},{"question":"In a CRM context, a product and service agreement (PSA)","choices":["A. defines product or service specifications. ","  B. is a type of customer communication. ","  C. is part of a promotional strategy to win back customers. ","  D. aligns customer groups with certain service levels. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"A product and service agreement does define specifications, but it does so in the context of segmenting customer groups. Customers are mapped and then aligned with different levels of customer service.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about customer segmentation is true?","choices":["A. Customer segmentation does not apply well to business (B2B) customers. ","  B. Demographic segmentation is not based on data about actual customer buying behaviors. ","  C. Customer segmentation may help increase revenue but is not a tool for increasing profitability. ","  D. Customer segmentation is a concept introduced in CRM. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Customer segmentation predates CRM but in the past relied heavily on demographic segmentation, which does not use actual customer buying behavior as CRM segmentation methods do. Customer segmentation can increase both revenue and profitability for retail as well as B2B customers.  "},{"question":"A supplier tracks shipments and sales and commits to ensuring that retailers have goods on hand. Retailers do not issue purchase orders. This describes","choices":["A. a quick response inventory management model. ","  B. a continuous replenishment inventory management model. ","  C. a vendor-managed inventory model. ","  D. none of the above. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"In a continuous replenishment model, suppliers are notified daily of actual sales or warehouse shipments and commit to replenishing inventory without receiving purchase orders.  "},{"question":"Vendor-managed inventory is an example of a collaborative initiative that can benefit supply chain participants by","choices":["A. enhancing demand. ","  B. lengthening intervals between restocking. ","  C. shortening production times. ","  D. reducing costs.  "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"In this arrangement, the manufacturer receives better information about market demand, enabling more efficient production and better inventory management, thereby reducing costs.  "},{"question":"CRM and SRM share a focus on","choices":["A. choosing appropriate strategic partners. ","  B. gathering and sharing information. ","  C. understanding buying habits of retail customers. ","  D. providing superior marketing decision support. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Both CRM and SRM focus on gathering information but for different purposes: CRM to understand customers better and support marketing, SRM to develop and manage relationships with key partners in the supply chain.  "},{"question":"\"A variety of activities all designed to position what the business is selling to the right people, at the right time, and in the right manner.\" This describes which component of a CRM strategy?","choices":["A. Price ","  B. Product ","  C. Placement ","  D. Promotion"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Promotion comprises a variety of marketing activities, from customer research through strategy setting and advertising. CRM enhances both the gathering of information about customers and the use of that information in marketing activities.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a good example of a virtual organization?","choices":["A. Merger of two competitors ","  B. Raw materials supplier that agrees to supply product for an upcoming production cycle ","  C. Strategic alliance of four companies to develop a new drug product and market it under the name of one of the companies ","  D. Company that sells only services, not products "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A virtual organization is a long-term strategic alliance of separate business entities that presents itself to third parties as a single entity.  "},{"question":"\"Customer care should, at this stage, promote strong brand identity and development of lifetime customers.\" This sentence best describes what phase of the product life cycle?","choices":["A. Introduction ","  B. Growth ","  C. Maturity ","  D. Decline"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"As sales decline, customer care becomes more critical. As distribution and sales decrease, customers with products that are becoming obsolete must be supported. Success now can win customers loyal to the brand. "},{"question":"Repeated transactions are funneled through an account manager and regulated through medium-term contracts. This best exemplifies which of the following types of business relationships?","choices":["A. Mergers and acquisitions ","  B. Ongoing relationship ","  C. Collaborations/strategic alliance ","  D. Buy the market"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"An ongoing relationship involves repeated transactions, perhaps regulated through medium-term contracts. Communication is funneled through an account manager, who adjusts in all interactions to the customer's culture and way of doing business.  "},{"question":"Supply chain participant priorities often conflict. Which of the following groups sets a priority on short order lead times and quick delivery turnaround time?","choices":["A. Suppliers ","  B. Warehousers ","  C. Manufacturers ","  D. Retailers "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Retailers need short order lead times and quick delivery turnaround times.  "},{"question":"SRM is collaborative rather than transactional. Allowing suppliers to participate in improving the supply chain system benefits SRM participants in which of the following ways?","choices":["A. Reduced marketing costs ","  B. Higher customer satisfaction ","  C. Cheaper products ","  D. Increased control by the alliance manager "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"In SRM's collaborative relationships, suppliers can participate in improving the system, which results in better product, higher customer satisfaction, and better customer retention.  "},{"question":"A \"best cost\" risk management outcome is derived by","choices":["A. subtracting cost of possible risk from cost of business and dividing that by likelihood of the occurrence. ","  B. multiplying the expected cost of the risk by its likelihood. ","  C. adding accumulated risk associated with all strategic suppliers. ","  D. subtracting cost of possible risk from cost of business.  "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A 'best cost\" analysis of risk is performed by multiplying the anticipated cost of the business disruption by the likelihood of its occurrence.  "},{"question":"In this long-term arrangement, suppliers are fully aware of the purchaser's goals and strategies and work with the purchaser to develop and implement tactics. This best exemplifies which of the following types of business relationships?","choices":["A. Collaborations/strategic alliance ","  B. Buy the market ","  C. Mergers and acquisitions ","  D. Ongoing relationship "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Collaborations or strategic alliances are long-term arrangements ruled more by agreements than contracts. The suppliers are fully aware of the purchaser's goals and strategies and work with the purchaser to develop and implement tactics. Trust levels are high.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is an example of the voice of the customer (VOC) technique?","choices":["A. Analysis of customer buying behaviors ","  B. Customer design groups ","  C. Collated comments of sales representatives calling on specific customer groups ","  D. Brief checkoff customer satisfaction surveys printed on invoices"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Customer design groups are an example of open-ended information gathering used by VOC to make complex customer perceptions more visible to a business. A brief checkoff survey does not capture complex information. Analysis of behaviors and analysis by others do not present the customer's own voice.  "},{"question":"In the supply chain model, CRM is instrumental in","choices":["A. creating and maintaining demand. ","  B. ensuring supply at the retail level. ","  C. aligning distributors with retailers. ","  D. eliminating volatility in orders of raw materials. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"In general, CRM benefits the supply chain by creating and maintaining demand for products and services.  "},{"question":"Establishing clear ground rules for collaboration and conflict resolution benefits both alliance participants by","choices":["A. ensuring strict adherence to the established alliance contract by both participants. ","  B. providing clear channels of legal redress for each participant. ","  C. preventing any sources of tension between participant organizations. ","  D. encouraging participants to redefine problematic connections rather than break them. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"In a dynamic marketplace, a static consultant contract without clear and flexible guidelines and processes to manage the relationship simply encourages consultants to break their connection with the company rather than redefine it.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a benefit of collaborative transportation management (CTM)?","choices":["A. Reduction of carriers' wait time for loading and unloading ","  B. Optimization of weight and volume capacity of network resources ","  C. Increase in backhaul opportunities for carriers ","  D. All of the above "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"CTMs can deliver all of these benefits by aligning transportation needs with transportation assets to eliminate inefficiencies, such as wait time, half-filled loads, or empty backhauls (\"deadheading\").  . "},{"question":"The Internet and intranets have benefited supplier relationship management through improved communication. Which of the following represents a benefit of the Internet and intranets to SRM?","choices":["A. Early detection of quality problems through timely information sharing ","  B. Better forecasting of raw materials and labor through synchronized planning activities ","  C. Decreased time-to-market through coordinating workflows ","  D. All of the above "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Improved, real-time communication can benefit supply relationships in all of the ways listed, from planning through production and distribution.  "},{"question":"Creation of brand image is a concern related to","choices":["A. product. ","  B. promotion. ","  C. placement. ","  D. pricing. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Pricing, product, and placement are all important strategy elements in implementing and maintaining brand image or identity, but creation of the desired image is a promotional activity.  "},{"question":"A vulnerable customer is one who","choices":["A. the competition has been selling intensively. ","  B. is segmented into a low-value group and offered little incentive. ","  C. is about to discontinue service or stop purchasing the brand products. ","  D. has bought product that is becoming obsolete. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The most accurate answer is that a vulnerable customer is one who is about to stop being a customer. This may be due to factors described in some of the incorrect choices. A vulnerable customer may perceive little value in the relationship, may have developed little loyalty, and may be willing to try a competitor. A customer with obsolete product who does not receive customer care may soon become vulnerable.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about outsourcing some supply chain activities to an off-site delivery center is true?","choices":["A. Off-site delivery centers typically offer 60 percent savings in total project costs. ","  B. Off-site delivery centers are used only when IT resources are required. ","  C. Off-site delivery centers may add value to the supply chain through better performance. ","  D. Off-site delivery centers reduce lead time because they typically offer faster performance. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Off-site delivery centers add value to the supply chain by performing tasks that require special expertise and resources, such as application and data management. They are not necessarily faster, but they have been shown to reduce technology project costs by up to 40 percent.  "},{"question":"Which SRM technology allows information collected by one application or supply chain partner to be shared by all applications or partners?","choices":["A. Wireless communication ","  B. Data warehousing and mining applications ","  C. Web-based procurement ","  D. Satellite-based tracking of transportation assets"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"While the other options are also valuable SRM tools, data warehousing and mining allow sharing of information between applications and partners.  "},{"question":"Which of the following factors has led to greater customer focus in business?","choices":["A. Higher quality of goods and services ","  B. Advances in technology ","  C. Greater global competition ","  D. All of the above "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"All of the answers are correct. Higher quality, made possible through technology, has created increased customer expectations, which has in turn led to price as a differentiating factor. This has created a downward pressure on profit margin. Greater customer focus helps counter this pressure.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a benefit of collaborative transportation management (CTM)?","choices":["A. Reduction of carriers' wait time for loading and unloading ","  B. Optimization of weight and volume capacity of network resources ","  C. Increase in backhaul opportunities for carriers ","  D. All of the above "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"CTMs can deliver all of these benefits by aligning transportation needs with transportation assets to eliminate inefficiencies, such as wait time, half-filled loads, or empty backhauls (\"deadheading\").  "},{"question":"In the Pareto principle, a significant percentage of a company's revenue or profits is derived from","choices":["A. less than 10 percent of the customer base. ","  B. about or less than 20 percent of the customer base. ","  C. about or less than 40 percent of the customer base. ","  D. about or less than 80 percent of the customer base. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The Pareto principle posits that a small percentage of the customer base (usually about or less than 20 percent) accounts for a large proportion of a company's revenue or profit (80 percent or more).  "},{"question":"Which of the following supply chain participants is likely to resist SCM efforts because they feel that e-marketplaces have the effect of reducing their products and services to a commodity?","choices":["A. Distributor ","  B. Customer ","  C. Supplier ","  D. Internal "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Many suppliers feel that e-marketplaces have the effect of reducing their products and services to a commodity where price is emphasized rather than quality or the partnership.  "},{"question":"Cost-effective and efficient collaboration between supply chain partners requires","choices":["A. maintaining separate decision-making structures to avoid conflicts. ","  B. a conflict resolution model. ","  C. structuring communication and decision making so that conflicts do not occur. ","  D. defining an early point at which to dissolve a troubled relationship."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Forging supplier relationships represents an investment that must be protected by developing ways to identify potential and actual conflicts, resolve them without endangering the relationship, and learning from the conflict.  "},{"question":"Supply chain participant priorities often conflict. Which of the following groups sets a priority on product and feature variety and price reduction?","choices":["A. Suppliers ","  B. Retailers ","  C. Customers ","  D. Manufacturers"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Customers demand a variety of products and features as well as low prices.  "},{"question":"An effective customer service management strategy includes which of the following?","choices":["A. Delivering consistent and identical customer service to all customer segments ","  B. Developing a general system but allowing flexibility to customer service personnel to develop specific procedures ","  C. Development of a product and service agreement (PSA) ","  D. Restricting customer interactions to a limited set of defined scenarios that may be performed within the existing infrastructure  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Development of the PSA, procedures to handle all customer interactions, infrastructure (people and information) to perform the procedures, and metrics to measure success are all parts of a successful customer service management strategy. Customer interaction scenarios are determined by customer needs, not by existing infrastructure. Specific responses should be developed and followed. Service levels may be customized for different customer segments.  "},{"question":"How does supply chain integration help resolve the conflict between greater product variety and reduced inventory demand?","choices":["A. By enabling delayed differentiation ","  B. By enabling direct warehouse-to-customer shipping ","  C. By combining shipments through cross-docking ","  D. By reducing lead times "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Shipping generic products and creating the customer variations further down the supply chain (delayed differentiation) aggregates customer demand across all products. This produces a more accurate demand forecast with a smaller degree of variability, allowing reduced storage of safety stock.  "},{"question":"\"A period marked by high costs and low sales.\" This phrase best describes what phase of the product life cycle?","choices":["A. Development ","  B. Introduction ","  C. Growth ","  D. Maturity  "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Because of costs associated with marketing, establishing inventory, and developing the distribution system and because a customer base has not yet been acquired, the introduction phase of the product life cycle is marked by high costs but low sales.  "},{"question":"Which of the following best describes a customer data warehouse (CDW)?","choices":["A. Current customer profiles stored in a database ","  B. Purchased data on specific customer segment ","  C. Data about customers, products, and marketplace extracted from internal and external resources ","  D. Repository of all data related to customer transactions "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A customer data warehouse (CDW) stores data about customers, products, and market trends, consolidating it in a manner that can facilitate future analysis to spot trends and relationships. "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about successful strategic supplier relationships is true?","choices":["A. No single restructuring of processes will be adequate. ","  B. Although marketplace change may be constant, the details of the relationship should not change. ","  C. Relationships should not be affected by the shifting priorities of the partners. ","  D. The best change occurs in large movements that motivate the entire organization rather than in smaller increments"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Supply partners must accept and commit to the fact of change in their relationships. As conditions and individual priorities and strategies change, the processes that define the relationship should change as well. It is better if change can be accomplished incrementally.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about the role of purchasing in an SRM model is correct?","choices":["A. Under an SRM model, strategic decisions such as selection of alliance partners are pushed down to subordinate purchasing roles. ","  B. Strategic sourcing has greatly simplified the tasks associated with purchasing. ","  C. SRM technology has greatly complicated the tasks of purchasing managers and agents. ","  D. Purchasing roles have become more layered between strategic management and buying. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Purchasing has, in fact, become more complex with the use of strategic sourcing. Roles have become more stratified, with senior-level managers focusing on strategic decisions and lower-level managers focusing on procurement and monitoring. They are aided by SRM technology, which has automated and supported many of their new tasks, such as partner research and contracting and invoice development.  "},{"question":"A company maintains a secondary outsourced transportation network capable of meeting the needs of its primary customer base. This is an example of","choices":["A. poor outsourcing practices. ","  B. outsourcing transportation needs. ","  C. using an off-site delivery center. ","  D. managing possible risks of SRM outsourcing."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"It is reasonable to outsource transportation, especially in a global marketplace. And it is an especially sound practice to manage risks associated with this outsourcing by maintaining a redundant supplier in the event of disruptions with the primary outsourced transportation network.  "},{"question":"Which of the following best describes what an organization's risk portfolio should do?","choices":["A. Identify current risk-prone partnerships that should be severed. ","  B. Balance risks in terms of probability, cost of occurrence, and cost of mitigation. ","  C. Eliminate risks by predicting their likely sources. ","  D. Identify those risk costs that can shifted to a partner's portfolio."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"After determining the nature and costs of potential disruptions, organizations assemble a desirable risk portfolio that balances risks in terms of probability, cost of occurrence, and cost of mitigation. "},{"question":"Supply chain participant priorities often conflict. Which of the following groups sets a priority on minimizing transportation costs and inventory levels?","choices":["A. Warehousers ","  B. Retailers ","  C. Manufacturers ","  D. Customers"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Logistics and warehousing management seek to minimize transportation costs by utilizing quantity discounts and minimizing inventory levels.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a benefit associated with customer segmentation?","choices":["A. Shorter time-to-market ","  B. Better ROI on promotion budgets ","  C. Shorter sales cycle ","  D. Lower production costs "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Customer segmentation allows businesses to learn customer desires and habits and design more effective promotional programs.  "},{"question":"A business gathers information from its accounts information system to identify those customers who have bought a large volume of items in the innovative product group. This is an example of","choices":["A. developing a PSA. ","  B. data mining. ","  C. data warehousing. ","  D. setting a channel strategy. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Data mining is the process of studying data to search for previously unknown relationships.   "},{"question":"CRM and SRM share a focus on","choices":["A. gathering and sharing information. ","  B. providing superior marketing decision support. ","  C. choosing appropriate strategic partners. ","  D. understanding buying habits of retail customers. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Both CRM and SRM focus on gathering information but for different purposes: CRM to understand customers better and support marketing, SRM to develop and manage relationships with key partners in the supply chain.  "},{"question":"In the supply chain model, CRM is instrumental in","choices":["A. ensuring supply at the retail level. ","  B. eliminating volatility in orders of raw materials. ","  C. aligning distributors with retailers. ","  D. creating and maintaining demand"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"In general, CRM benefits the supply chain by creating and maintaining demand for products and services.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about customer segmentation is true?","choices":["A. Customer segmentation does not apply well to business (B2B) customers. ","  B. Customer segmentation is a concept introduced in CRM. ","  C. Customer segmentation may help increase revenue but is not a tool for increasing profitability. ","  D. Demographic segmentation is not based on data about actual customer buying behaviors. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Customer segmentation predates CRM but in the past relied heavily on demographic segmentation, which does not use actual customer buying behavior as CRM segmentation methods do. Customer segmentation can increase both revenue and profitability for retail as well as B2B customers.  "},{"question":"Why does market volatility create greater need for supply chain integration?","choices":["A. Integration enables a global response to demands. ","  B. Integration helps counter consumers' and competitors' increased access to information. ","  C. Integration helps reduce conflicts of interest. ","  D. Integration enables demand enhancement. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Consumers and competitors have more and faster access to information, causing market volatility. Supply chain integration provides comparable improvements in information access.  "},{"question":"Which one of these companies is practicing good SRM risk management?","choices":["A. This company develops detailed plans to shift work orders among several certified global suppliers in the event of labor disruptions in their countries. ","  B. This company relies on the selection process as its only means of risk management. ","  C. This company requires in its contracts that all suppliers use a defined third-party transportation provider for all shipments. ","  D. This company sources a key raw material from one supplier who reliably provides the lowest price. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Single sourcing of a key material or component is not a good example of risk management, even if the supplier is the lowest-cost provider. Good risk management may involve additional costs incurred through maintaining redundancy in the supply chain and requiring additional supplier performance or assumption of risk. "},{"question":"A business is attempting to create more powerful bonds between its customers and itself by delivering greater customer satisfaction and mutual dependence. This business is pursing a strategy of","choices":["A. creating lifetime customers. ","  B. customer segmentation. ","  C. competitive differentiation. ","  D. niche marketing. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"While businesses may employ customer segmentation, competitive differentiation, and niche marketing to appeal to customers, this strategy describes the creation of lifetime customers.  "},{"question":"A company performs transportation of both materials and finished product for a global manufacturer. To manage fluctuations in demand, they contract with service providers in geographical regions, who in turn manage contracts with individual suppliers. This best describes a","choices":["A. distributor integration (DI) network. ","  B. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network. ","  C. third-party logistics (3PL) company. ","  D. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Fourth-party logistics providers are often found in global markets where they can combine the resources of suppliers and often 3PLs to meet the challenges of time zone, geographical, and cultural differences.  "},{"question":"You are ordering a camping tent through a call center for a recreational equipment manufacturer. The operator notes that for a little more money you could receive significantly more value in another tent model. This is an example of","choices":["A. up-selling. ","  B. a loyalty program. ","  C. cross-selling. ","  D. a win-back program"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Up-selling is a CRM tactic in which customers are offered higher-priced or more profitable items instead of the item they were originally considering. The operator in this case may be supported by a workflow that suggests specific models and links to more data in an electronic catalog or data about the customer's previous purchases that suggest a tendency toward higher-priced purchases.  "},{"question":"\"The most profitable period but also the period most vulnerable to competitive inroads.\" This phrase best describes what phase of the product life cycle?","choices":["A. Development ","  B. Introduction ","  C. Growth ","  D. Maturity"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"During the maturity phase of the product life cycle, the costs of acquiring sales are declining, so profit is higher. At the same time, growing competition places pressure on prices. Increased sales promotion and aggressive customer acquisition help balance this influence. "},{"question":"An SCM initiative's strategic plan must address which of the following issues?","choices":["A. Communicating the business rationale for the initiative ","  B. Defining how physical assets and resources will be reduced ","  C. Defining the architecture to be used for the company's intranet ","  D. How the network will be differentiated across the full chain "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"A strategic plan addresses how the network will be differentiated across the full chain, the architecture used for Internet and intranet supply chain features, how physical assets and resources will be shared, and who will be in charge of executing each of the major changes needed.  "},{"question":"A customer-focused business","choices":["A. focuses on customer care rather than product/service design and delivery. ","  B. educates customers throughout the purchasing process. ","  C. restricts communication and distribution channels to the most profitable options. ","  D. gathers information about the customer but restricts its use to critical points in the supply chain"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Customer-focused businesses try to make their customers feel better educated about what they are buying before, during, and after the purchase. They promote sharing of information about the customer throughout the supply chain, appreciate the need to consider customer needs in designing as well as marketing and distributing products, and maintain communication and distribution strategies that value convenience for the customer more than profitability.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the best example of risk mitigation in a strategic alliance?","choices":["A. Improving operations by lowering system costs. ","  B. Overcoming barriers to market entry. ","  C. Surmounting limited availability of component suppliers. ","  D. Improving overall financial position. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"From a purely reactive stance, companies with certain types of supply situations may be able to manage risk better in a strategic alliance. Purchasers must consider the strategic importance of the component, the complexity of the component-product interface, the number of component suppliers available, and the uncertainty of the supplier relationship. "},{"question":"\"A technological advance that has led to both greater global competition and collaboration.\" This might best describe","choices":["A. the Internet. ","  B. the intranet. ","  C. advanced telephony features. ","  D. the computer. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"While the computer, intranets, and advanced telephony have certainly enhanced both supplier and customer relationship management, the Internet has made the largest impact on communication with customers and between partners in the supply chain. "},{"question":"Central to implementing an SRM strategy is the use of PSAs (product and service agreements). Which of the following statements about PSAs between strategic partners is correct?","choices":["A. The PSA is not subject to standard strategic goal metrics. ","  B. The negotiated PSA must be mutually beneficial for both partners. ","  C. The PSA is crafted only after a carefully conducted pilot program. ","  D. PSAs should be standardized for all suppliers"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A PSA between partners should be mutually beneficial. It may be customized, should precede pilot and full implementation, and should always be measured for improvement.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following is required for successful implementation of CRM and/or SRM strategies?","choices":["A. New job definitions ","  B. A new workforce ","  C. Greater control from the top down ","  D. Greater emphasis on task-focused responsibility centers"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Organizations implementing CRM and SRM must move toward greater collaboration and away from more hierarchical structures defined by task-focused responsibility centers and top-down decision making. They call for a new attitude and new skills in the existing workforce.  "},{"question":"SRM has been used in the parts/after-market industry to","choices":["A. implement both production and sales tactics. ","  B. retool aging technology. ","  C. gather information about customers. ","  D. select suppliers."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"SRM has been used in the parts or after-market industry to plan both strategy and tactics as well as to budget and manage specific business events, such as managing inventory.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about a customer data warehouse (CDW) is correct?","choices":["A. One-to-one marketing cannot be achieved without using a CDW. ","  B. CDWs are primarily used as measurement tools. ","  C. CDWs are maintained as separate entities from a company's customer databases. ","  D. None of the above "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Because it allows a high degree of customization, one-to-one marketing programs cannot be implemented without using a CDW. CDWs are used for a variety of purposes, including segmentation, implementing different offers to customers, analyzing buying behaviors to detect preferences, and supporting strategic decisions, such as the allocation of human resources. They are usually used in conjunction with information from a company's other databases.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about the certification process is correct?","choices":["A. Criteria should be adjusted to individual suppliers' capabilities. ","  B. Suppliers should be clearly informed of criteria and processes to be used in the certification process. ","  C. Certification is a supplier selection tool only. ","  D. All potential suppliers should go through the certification process. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"To achieve certification's highest potential, companies must clearly communicate what they will be measuring and how. Criteria should be consistent from one supplier to the next. The outcome can be used not only for selection but also for supplier improvement. Companies usually opt to pursue the certification process only with actual or key suppliers.  "},{"question":"The cost considerations that SCM partner organizations must examine include all of the following except","choices":["A. Are there consulting fees involved? ","  B. What are the hardware expenses? ","  C. How profitable are each of the partner SCM organizations? ","  D. What are the overhead expenses?"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Cost considerations that SCM partner organizations must examine include costs of hardware, software, overhead, and consulting fees.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about CRM strategy components is true?","choices":["A. Promotion in CRM is distinctly different from traditional marketing strategies. ","  B. The starting point for product design is the customer. ","  C. Price is determined primarily by the cost of production. ","  D. Placement is determined primarily by product specifications. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Successful product designs begin with knowledge of the customer's needs and buying habits. Promotional activities are greatly supported and enhanced by CRM abilities, but promotion decisions, goals, and activities are, for the most part, unchanged from the traditional marketing model. Price may be determined by a number of factors, as may placement.  "},{"question":"Which of the following best defines a virtual organization?","choices":["A. Short-term tactical alliance in which partnering companies remain distinct and visible to end users ","  B. Potentially long-term relationship between separate business entities to design, produce, and distribute a product ","  C. Merger of separate entities with common business values and goals to gain better market position ","  D. Separate entities that collaborate to design and sell intangible products and services "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A virtual organization is best described as a short-term alliance of independent businesses for a potentially long-term relationship. Businesses cooperate to design, create, and distribute product (including services) based on shared values and are perceived by third parties as a single entity.  "},{"question":"Supply chain participant priorities often conflict. Which of the following groups sets a priority on high production output and low production costs?","choices":["A. Manufacturers ","  B. Retailers ","  C. Customers ","  D. Suppliers "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Manufacturing organizations strive for high production output and low production costs.  "},{"question":"For which of the following companies would implementing SRM probably be most critical?","choices":["A. A gift catalog company that offers a large number of items from a wide variety of suppliers ","  B. An Internet banking company seeking to expand use among high-value customers ","  C. A company that uses raw materials and prefabricated components to create consumer goods ","  D. A company competing in a commodity market with little opportunity for adding value "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"SRM focuses on identifying opportunities for strategic relationships between supply chain partners and on developing and managing those relationships. The Internet banking company is concerned primarily with customers rather than suppliers. The commodity-driven company may have some benefit, but it will be limited by the opportunities to add value. Similarly, the gift catalog company requires adequate supply at the right times but may rely on so many suppliers that strategic partnerships are not practical. The manufacturer of consumer goods will benefit from developing strategic relationships with suppliers that add value and make its products more competitive.   "},{"question":"Which of the following capability improvement goals are proactive reasons for forming a strategic alliance?","choices":["A. Improving management compensation programs ","  B. Acquiring technological expertise in weaker areas of the company ","  C. Improving time to market or increasing quality ","  D. Acquiring competitive high-tech equipment "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Proactive reasons for an organization to consider a strategic alliance are the alliance's ability to add value to products, enable strategic growth, increase market access, strengthen operations, increase organizational expertise, build organizational skills, and enhance financial strength.  "},{"question":"Which of the following benefits applies to lifetime customers?","choices":["A. They are more difficult to satisfy than first-time or short-term customers. ","  B. They increase total marketing costs. ","  C. They increase the need for CRM activities. ","  D. They tend to have a null effect on revenue but a positive effect on profit. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Lifetime customers increase the need for CRM, but they also make it a little easier as the business learns more about them over time. Total marketing costs decline, satisfaction increases with better customer understanding, and both revenue and profit increase.  "},{"question":"The five best practices for supply chains include which of the following?","choices":["A. Advertising and sales analysis ","  B. Strategic sourcing and supplier management ","  C. Outsourcing operations and logistics ","  D. Maximizing profits"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The five best practices for supply chains are strategic sourcing and supplier management, operations and logistics, customer relationship management and channels, information technology, and change management.  "},{"question":"A retailer replenishes stock by ordering new goods from a manufacturer on a one-to-one replacement basis. This describes","choices":["A. a quick response inventory management model. ","  B. a continuous replenishment inventory management model. ","  C. a vendor-managed inventory model. ","  D. none of the above. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"In a quick response model, the retailer continues to order from the supplier, although the supplier may collect POS data for the purposes of planning and forecasting.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about purchased customer data is true?","choices":["A. They can be very broad. ","  B. They are very useful in managing relationships with existing customers. ","  C. They may be more useful in new customer acquisition. ","  D. They paint a picture of a business's own customers."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Data purchased from companies such as database marketing companies provide information about customers outside a company's own customer base. These data are useful in reaching new customers.  "},{"question":"SRM increases the visibility of the entire supply chain. This benefits SRM participants in which of the following ways?","choices":["A. Lowers the number of required distributors ","  B. Simplifies market segmentation ","  C. Enables faster response and better contingency planning ","  D. Reduces customer service calls"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Increased supply chain visibility can lessen the bullwhip effect and enable early problem detection, faster response and better contingency planning, and stronger relationships because of increased trust.  "},{"question":"A company manages catalog purchasing of stationery products and computer equipment for corporate headquarters. It provides invoicing to its clients by requisitioning department customers and delivers product. This best describes a","choices":["A. third-party logistics (3PL) company. ","  B. distributor integration (DI) network. ","  C. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network. ","  D. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"This company is probably a third-party logistics provider, a company that performs all or part of an organization's procurement of materials and distribution.  "},{"question":"Rather than choosing the least expensive component for its computers, an electronics manufacturer factors in the costs of reverse logistics. This best exemplifies which of the following distinctions between traditional purchasing and strategic sourcing?","choices":["A. Transactional versus collaborative ","  B. Limited visibility versus entire supply chain visibility ","  C. Purchase price versus total cost of ownership ","  D. Boundary-specific versus realigned work processes and workflows "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"There is a distinction between price and total cost of ownership. For example, a manufacturer of electronics may choose a component based on the lowest price, but that choice may not translate into low cost if the low-priced components are not reliable and fail early.  "},{"question":"The steps for successfully implementing a strategic supplier alliance include","choices":["A. developing employee negotiation and joint problem solving skills. ","  B. establishing a well-defined purchasing contract with potential partners. ","  C. avoiding conflicts throughout the relationship. ","  D. thinking in terms of the overall goals of the channel master. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Because collaboration skills may not come naturally to everyone, firms must develop their employees' skills for resolving conflicts, negotiating, solving problems jointly, and conducting difficult conversations. Conflicts are unavoidable but must be treated as learning experiences. Agreements must be flexible. Alliance managers must focus on the overall goals of the alliance rather than those of the channel master.  "},{"question":"In a supply chain, distributors can refer customers to other distributors who have needed product on hand. This best describes a","choices":["A. third-party logistics (3PL) company. ","  B. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network. ","  C. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. ","  D. distributor integration (DI) network"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Using modern information and communication systems, distributor integration relationships allow distributors to share access to product and service.  "},{"question":"Which of the following supply chain participants is likely to resist initial SCM efforts because they feel that they are lost in the network, never knowing whom to contact or how to check on an order?","choices":["A. Distributor ","  B. Internal ","  C. Customer ","  D. Supplier"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Initially, customers may complain of getting lost in the network and never knowing whom to contact or how to check on an order. This is particularly common when more than one organization is involved in the support of a product or service.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is an enterprise business system (EBS) backbone application?","choices":["A. Managing EDI with suppliers ","  B. Managing online bidding sessions ","  C. Order history ","  D. Product cataloging"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"EBS backbone applications focus on gathering, storing, and reporting information that is necessary to perform other functions in the SRM system, such as data on order history and accounting and information about suppliers and their performance.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about vendor-managed inventory is true?","choices":["A. Inventory data cannot be tied to MPS or MRP. ","  B. Inventory levels can be adjusted according to different variables. ","  C. Retailers maintain oversight on ordering. ","  D. Retailers have no hand in setting initial inventory; historical data are used. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Although vendors may suggest inventory levels, retailers must approve initial levels. After that point, levels will be maintained by the vendor according to an agreement and models based on POS and shipment data for greatest customer satisfaction and return on inventory. Data can be tied into planning processes so that MPSs can be created and MRPs set.  "},{"question":"\"Customer interest is high, and supply must be managed to meet demand and avoid stockouts that could boost growing competition.\" This sentence best describes what phase of the product life cycle?","choices":["A. Development ","  B. Introduction ","  C. Growth ","  D. Maturity "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"During the growth phase, the customer base increases and competitors begin to enter the market. Data on the growing customer base must be analyzed for new opportunities, and supply must be managed to meet growing demand.  "},{"question":"A purchaser and its suppliers form an ongoing relationship in which they all participate in improving the system. This best exemplifies which of the following distinctions between traditional purchasing and strategic sourcing?","choices":["A. Limited visibility versus entire supply chain visibility ","  B. Boundary-specific versus realigned work processes and workflows ","  C. Purchase price versus true cost ","  D. Transactional versus collaborative "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Traditional purchasing sees each purchase as a discrete transaction. Since strategic sourcing involves ongoing relationships, there is opportunity for collaboration between the purchaser and suppliers that can result in improving the profitability of the supply chain and adding value to the final product or service.  "},{"question":"A company invites key business customers to participate in the performance evaluations of its account managers. This is an example of","choices":["A. voice of the customer information gathering. ","  B. collaborative management practices. ","  C. supply chain integration. ","  D. measuring customer satisfaction. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Measurement of customer satisfaction is a key element of CRM. B2B companies may measure the CRM effectiveness of their account managers by inviting the managers' customers to participate in their performance evaluations. VOC is considered a more general research tool.   "},{"question":"Supply chain integration allows the reduction of safety stock levels, which benefits participants by","choices":["A. enhancing demand. ","  B. lowering inventory levels and reducing costs. ","  C. shortening cycle times. ","  D. improving the ability to anticipate needs and convey benefits."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"With shorter lead and cycle times, the level of safety stock may be reduced, which leads to savings by reducing inventory levels and obsolescence costs.  "},{"question":"Which of the following best describes the critical difference between traditional and current supply chain management approaches?","choices":["A. The focus has shifted from human resource-based solutions to technology-driven solutions. ","  B. The focus has shifted from brick-and-mortar solutions to Web-based solutions. ","  C. The focus has shifted from internal quality improvement and cost reduction to collaborative solutions up and down the supply chain. ","  D. The focus has shifted from inventory management to demand enhancement. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"While in the past the strategic focus for many organizations was to improve their internal quality and reduce costs, the new focus is on implementing total supply chain solutions that require collaboration from partner organizations both upstream and downstream.  "},{"question":"For which of the following companies would CRM probably be a priority?","choices":["A. A company with a customer base with diverse needs and interests ","  B. A company that provides raw materials for an extended supply chain in which value is added at later points in the chain ","  C. A company with one large customer who specifies product/service features ","  D. A company that performs purchasing for a large manufacturer from several strategic suppliers "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"CRM focuses on learning more about one's customers and using this knowledge to enhance product, increase customer satisfaction, and improve revenue and profit. The company with the diverse customer base can potentially benefit greatly from being able to gather and use more information about its customers. "},{"question":"A company fears that it will be overcome in the marketplace by a competitor who is developing a new technology that will give it dominance. In response, the company forms an alliance with a supply chain partner. They invest equally in creating the infrastructure to support the alliance, revise their corporate visions and organizational structure, and create processes to share information and merge workflows. Yet, the alliance may fail because it lacks","choices":["A. investment. ","  B. individual excellence. ","  C. integration. ","  D. information. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Successful alliances begin from a position of mutual strength and excellence. In this case, one partner is driven primarily by a desire to escape the problem of looming competition. This will be a hard obstacle to overcome even though the partners have invested in the relationship and integrated their organizations.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about the challenges of implementing CRM and SRM strategies is true?","choices":["A. Managers must acquire new skill sets. ","  B. Decision making must become more centralized and uniform. ","  C. Technology is too complex and expensive. ","  D. None of the above"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"As structures and processes change, managers will need to acquire new skills to support implementation of SRM and CRM. Decision making will actually move downward throughout the organization, closer to critical points in the supply chain. Technology is increasingly available, powerful, and easy to integrate.  "},{"question":"Supply chain integration provides which of the following?","choices":["A. Increased warehousing capacities ","  B. Reduced forecast accuracy ","  C. Lower shortage costs ","  D. Lower information technology cost"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Information sharing benefits organizations by improving forecasts, improving coordination of manufacturing and distribution systems and strategies, reducing lead times, and accelerating reactions to marketing data. Information technology costs may increase but are offset by other benefits.  "},{"question":"An example of a supplier performance reporting mechanism is","choices":["A. a floor failure event rate. ","  B. an automated performance alert. ","  C. a certification document. ","  D. a rejected materials rate."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Rates, such as number of floor failures, rejected materials, or delays in shipment, are used to compile reports of supplier performance but are not themselves reports. Reporting mechanisms include such tools as scorecards, performance failure alerts (which are online and in real time), and surveys. A certification indicates that a supplier has met criteria but does not report ongoing performance.  "},{"question":"\"A strategic decision, based on competition, perceived value, and brand identity.\" This describes which component of a CRM strategy?","choices":["A. Promotion ","  B. Price ","  C. Placement ","  D. Product"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Pricing is influenced by many factors other than cost of production, including competitive positions, customers' willingness to pay for the value received, and consistency with the brand identity that has been created.  "},{"question":"The best definition of the phrase \"contact channel strategy\" is","choices":["A. choosing media for advertising. ","  B. selection of key distributors of service or product. ","  C. designing a two-way communication architecture between customers and businesses. ","  D. none of the above."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Contact channel strategy may include the choice of advertising media and designing a distribution system, but it includes more concerns and is more interactive than those choices suggest. The contact channel strategy should address both contacting customers and being contacted by customers.  "},{"question":"How does supply chain integration help resolve the conflict between reduced cost and improved customer service?","choices":["A. By supporting factory-distributor-retailer-customer distribution pathways ","  B. By enabling direct shipping from warehouse to customer's home ","  C. By combining shipments through cross-docking ","  D. By enabling delayed differentiation"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Direct shipping from the warehouse to the customer's home lowers costs by storing inventory at a centrally located warehouse rather than at the retail location. Customer service is improved by allowing a larger selection of inventory and providing front-door delivery service.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the key to enabling supply chains to more quickly respond to customer demand and increase participants' profitability?","choices":["A. Creating an alliance with a key supplier ","  B. Collaborative planning across the entire supply chain ","  C. Creating individual partnerships ","  D. Information sharing with key partners"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The key is collaborative planning across the supply chain rather than mere information sharing or single alliances.  "},{"question":"A supplier tracks shipments and sales and commits to ensuring that retailers have goods on hand. Retailers do not issue purchase orders. This describes","choices":["A. a quick response inventory management model. ","  B. a continuous replenishment inventory management model. ","  C. a vendor-managed inventory model. ","  D. none of the above."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"In a continuous replenishment model, suppliers are notified daily of actual sales or warehouse shipments and commit to replenishing inventory without receiving purchase orders.  "},{"question":"The first step to successfully implement a strategic supplier alliance should be to","choices":["A. align internally by identifying key issues and stakeholders. ","  B. select the proper partners by evaluating corporate culture and operating style. ","  C. establish ground rules for how partners will work together and resolve conflict. ","  D. appoint a dedicated alliance manager to oversee the partner relationship. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Before entering alliances, start identifying key issues and decisions and involving key stakeholders for fewer surprises and greater buy-in by key people.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is part of the correct definition of customer relationship management?","choices":["A. Tool to support existing and potential customer needs ","  B. Solely a marketing philosophy ","  C. Tool to manage marketing, sales, supply planning, and production scheduling ","  D. Focused on forecasting and analysis of information "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Information gathered in the CRM process is used to support service to customers and potential customers and sales and marketing decisions, not resource and production planning.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a good example of a virtual organization?","choices":["A. Strategic alliance of four companies to develop a new drug product and market it under the name of one of the companies ","  B. Merger of two competitors ","  C. Company that sells only services, not products ","  D. Raw materials supplier that agrees to supply product for an upcoming production cycle "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A virtual organization is a long-term strategic alliance of separate business entities that presents itself to third parties as a single entity.  "},{"question":"Successful implementation of CRM and SRM philosophies usually requires","choices":["A. redefinition of core competencies. ","  B. outsourcing to companies with special expertise. ","  C. common business goals and mission statements for all supply chain members. ","  D. revision of decision-making processes."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Implementing CRM and SRM does not require that companies change their core competencies, although employees may need to acquire new skills. Nor do organizations need to form common goals or mission statements. They will need, however, to revisit work processes, job definitions, and decision-making structures.  "},{"question":"After selecting the proper partner, the next step in creating a successful alliance is to","choices":["A. establish ground rules. ","  B. engage in a collaborative corporate mindset. ","  C. negotiate a win-win deal. ","  D. appoint an alliance manager. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Before the rules, supervision, and improvement of the relationship can be pursued, a win-win deal must be negotiated. This sets the tone for the future alliance.  "},{"question":"\"The design and implementation of two-way communication between a business and its customers.\" This describes which component of a CRM strategy?","choices":["A. Price ","  B. Product ","  C. Placement ","  D. Promotion "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The traditional marketing definition of placement has been expanded to include not only getting product into the hands of customers (distribution) but also the customer's ability to access the business (e.g., for information, actual sales, or support).  "},{"question":"\"A variety of activities all designed to position what the business is selling to the right people, at the right time, and in the right manner.\" This describes which component of a CRM strategy?","choices":["A. Price ","  B. Placement ","  C. Promotion ","  D. Product"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Promotion comprises a variety of marketing activities, from customer research through strategy setting and advertising. CRM enhances both the gathering of information about customers and the use of that information in marketing activities.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about ISO certification is correct?","choices":["A. ISO certification has limited recognition globally. ","  B. ISO certification may be one criterion a supplier must meet in a larger certification process. ","  C. ISO certification is a one-time process. ","  D. Because of their depth, ISO standards can often be used in place of a company's own supplier criteria in the supplier certification process. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"ISO certification is a globally recognized process that certifying companies must update every three years. Since it is industry- rather than business-specific, it often complements a business's own certification process. ISO certification may be a requirement for suppliers, but because of the certification's broad criteria it is usually not the only requirement in the certification process.  "},{"question":"Lifetime customers","choices":["A. are increasingly more expensive for a business to maintain as they become more demanding. ","  B. can increase revenue but have a neutral effect on profit. ","  C. have forged a win-win relationship with the business in question. ","  D. are common in commodity markets driven by price rather than value."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Lifetime customers have a win-win relationship with the businesses they frequent. The customers gain greater satisfaction while the business enjoys decreased marketing costs and increased revenue and profit potential. Lifetime customers are not common in markets competing on price rather than added value.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is an example of the voice of the customer (VOC) technique?","choices":["A. Analysis of customer buying behaviors ","  B. Collated comments of sales representatives calling on specific customer groups ","  C. Customer design groups ","  D. Brief checkoff customer satisfaction surveys printed on invoices "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Customer design groups are an example of open-ended information gathering used by VOC to make complex customer perceptions more visible to a business. A brief checkoff survey does not capture complex information. Analysis of behaviors and analysis by others do not present the customer's own voice.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about the role of SRM in the supply chain model is correct?","choices":["A. It helps ensure the same profitability for all supply chain elements. ","  B. It focuses on meeting demand. ","  C. It focuses on gaining information about customers. ","  D. It measures success only by satisfaction of end customers. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"SRM helps ensure that demand created by CRM can be fulfilled in a manner profitable for all supply chain partners while maintaining customer satisfaction. Success of supplier relationships may be measured by various means, including time-to-market, cost efficiency, competitive advantage, and end customer satisfaction.  "},{"question":"Inventory status, capacity status and plans, production schedules, and shipment and demand forecasts are all shared by all parties on a real-time, online basis. This best exemplifies which of the following distinctions between traditional purchasing and strategic sourcing?","choices":["A. Boundary-specific versus realigned work processes and workflows ","  B. Limited visibility versus entire supply chain visibility ","  C. Transactional versus collaborative ","  D. Purchase price versus true cost"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"When information from suppliers, manufacturers, distributors, retailers, and customers is available for analysis, there is enhanced visibility of the supply chain and opportunities for improvement. Demand information, inventory status, capacity status, capacity plans, production schedules, promotion plans, shipment forecasts, and demand forecasts are all shared and ideally can be accessed by all parties on a real-time, online basis.  "},{"question":"In a CRM context, a product and service agreement (PSA)","choices":["A. is a type of customer communication. ","  B. defines product or service specifications. ","  C. aligns customer groups with certain service levels.  ","  D. is part of a promotional strategy to win back customers. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A product and service agreement does define specifications, but it does so in the context of segmenting customer groups. Customers are mapped and then aligned with different levels of customer service.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about strategic alliances is true?","choices":["A. In alliance relationships, flexibility is not a good thing. Processes must be rigidly followed and enforced. ","  B. Despite potential benefits, there has been little growth in the development of strategic alliances. ","  C. Alliances are relationships between two or more partners in the supply chain. ","  D. Alliance relationships are marked by organizational integration at a few critical points."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Alliance relationships are marked by organization integration at many points in the partners' organizations, from information systems through marketing and sales to finance.   "},{"question":"Which of the following is the best example of a promotion activity in a CRM strategy?","choices":["A. Creating a product and service agreement (PSA) ","  B. Segmenting customers according to their value to the business ","  C. Deciding where to distribute one's products ","  D. Charging less if a customer orders through the Internet "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Segmenting customers is an essential part of creating a promotional strategy, one of the four Ps of traditional marketing and CRM strategies. The other choices reflect those other components of a CRM strategy: product, price, and placement.  "},{"question":"Establishing clear ground rules for collaboration and conflict resolution benefits both alliance participants by","choices":["A. ensuring strict adherence to the established alliance contract by both participants. ","  B. encouraging participants to redefine problematic connections rather than break them. ","  C. providing clear channels of legal redress for each participant. ","  D. preventing any sources of tension between participant organizations. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"In a dynamic marketplace, a static consultant contract without clear and flexible guidelines and processes to manage the relationship simply encourages consultants to break their connection with the company rather than redefine it.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about effective supplier performance measurement systems is true?","choices":["A. They enable each department within an organization to define its own supplier performance measurement procedures. ","  B. They track the performance of a narrowly defined portion of the supply chain base. ","  C. Their performance measurements, reporting, and improvements should be unilaterally defined by the purchasing organization. ","  D. They automate key supplier performance measurement activities. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Effective supplier performance measurement systems track the performance of a broad portion of the supply chain base; collaborate with suppliers on performance measurements, reporting, and improvements; automate key supplier performance measurement activities; and standardize supplier performance measurement procedures across the organization.  "},{"question":"Supply chain participant priorities often conflict. Which of the following groups sets a priority on short order lead times and quick delivery turnaround time?","choices":["A. Suppliers ","  B. Manufacturers ","  C. Warehousers ","  D. Retailers "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Retailers need short order lead times and quick delivery turnaround times.   "},{"question":"A chief customer officer (CCO) is in charge of","choices":["A. identifying and responding to customer care opportunities. ","  B. identifying opportunities for enhancing revenue and profit through customer interactions. ","  C. assigning account managers to high-value customers. ","  D. responding to customer dissatisfaction."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A chief customer officer may supervise management of customer dissatisfaction, but the job entails more activities, including identifying customer touch points, defining and enforcing service standards, enriching the customer experience, and helping customers navigate within the organization.  "},{"question":"Which of the following supply chain participants is likely to resist SCM efforts initially because they feel that they can't trust any of their supply chain partners enough to share valuable data?","choices":["A. Customer ","  B. Internal ","  C. Supplier ","  D. Distributor"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Organizations' internal members are sometimes hesitant initially to trust any of their supply chain partners enough to share what they value as important internal information or data. While most organizations are open to receiving information regarding best practices from partner organizations, they are typically not willing to reciprocate by sharing equal information.  "},{"question":"An organization whose IT and operations groups are able to collaborate easily is best described as","choices":["A. farseeing. ","  B. cross-functional. ","  C. able to lead. ","  D. change-oriented. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A cross-functional organization is one that enjoys cooperation between internal groups, especially IT and operations.  "},{"question":"Supply chain participant priorities often conflict. Which of the following groups sets a priority on flexible delivery times, large volumes, and consistent materials mixes?","choices":["A. Warehouse managers ","  B. Suppliers ","  C. Logistics managers ","  D. Retailers"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Suppliers of raw materials typically prefer flexible delivery times, large yet stable volume demands, and consistency in mix of materials.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about implementing CRM technology is correct?","choices":["A. Implementation teams should represent technological areas only. ","  B. Systems should be measured against whether they increase efficiency and meet customer expectations. ","  C. Detailed architecture design at an early stage may lead to an inflexible system that is difficult to change. ","  D. If technology is optimal, job responsibilities may remain static in the new system. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Good CRM technology is easy to use and meets customer expectations. Successful implementation of CRM technology rests on a clear, well-thought-out architecture. Rather than inhibiting change, good design enhances integration and lessens the chances of conflicts as the system evolves. Since it may involve redefining jobs, implementation teams should be cross-functional.  "},{"question":"Which of the following tasks is most likely to be performed by a purchasing agent/planner rather than a purchasing manager?","choices":["A. Analyzing value of supply process ","  B. Selecting suppliers ","  C. Negotiating contracts with strategic sourcing partners ","  D. Order placement "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Purchasing managers focus on strategic tasks such as supplier selection, contract negotiation, and analysis and evaluation of the supply system. Purchasing agents or planners focus on placing orders, following up with suppliers as needed, monitoring supply needs, and measuring supplier performance.  "},{"question":"In the CRM business model, strategic pricing","choices":["A. must be continually analyzed to ensure that it is attractive to customers but still profitable to the business. ","  B. is calculated by a sliding scale based upon customers' ability to pay. ","  C. is calculated by adding a competitive profit margin to the total costs of creation, sales, and overhead. ","  D. must be consistent across targeted customer segments. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Pricing is generally a strategic decision, based on competition, perceived value, and brand identity. Strategic pricing must be carefully and frequently analyzed to ensure that the pricing structure is attractive to customers but still profitable to the business.  "},{"question":"In an SRM environment, a framework of performance metrics should be established to","choices":["A. monitor and identify opportunities for improvement. ","  B. achieve 50 percent adherence and adaptation by all partners. ","  C. penalize partners who do not adhere to agreed rules. ","  D. achieve annual cost reduction of 10 percent."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"One of the reasons to establish metrics and then monitor performance is to identify opportunities to improve supplier performance.  "},{"question":"Which of the following companies is most likely to be interested in SRM?","choices":["A. Company that performs market research for political candidates ","  B. Company that produces video games ","  C. Paint manufacturer that purchases chemicals and dyes from various suppliers ","  D. Credit card company "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Companies whose ability to meet customer demands rests on their control over the supply side of the supply chain model will be most interested in SRM. The other companies are primarily concerned with understanding and responding to customer needs and expectations.  "},{"question":"SRM structures and supports relationships with suppliers, thereby assisting in which of the following?","choices":["A. Improving depth of purchased parts knowledge ","  B. Reducing procurement and excess inventory costs ","  C. Targeting suppliers for cross-selling and up-selling opportunities ","  D. Focusing on cost of materials and components "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"SRM is a methodology to structure and support relationships with suppliers that will assist in reducing procurement and excess inventory costs, supporting a customer-focused business that delivers product/service customization and quality in the desired time frame, and improving processes in an ongoing manner.  "},{"question":"Suppliers are folded into the purchasing entity, business goals are shared, and competition has been eliminated. This best exemplifies which of the following types of business relationships?","choices":["A. Mergers and acquisitions ","  B. Ongoing relationship ","  C. Buy the market ","  D. Collaborations/strategic alliance "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"In mergers and acquisitions, suppliers are folded into the purchasing entity. Business goals are shared; business areas participate in setting strategy and planning integration of capabilities, processes, and information. Competition has been eliminated.  "},{"question":"Which of the following component purchasing goals are reactive or defensive reasons for forming a strategic alliance?","choices":["A. Opening new markets ","  B. Building organizational expertise ","  C. Adding value to products ","  D. The number of suppliers able to provide the component "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"From a purely reactive stance, companies with certain types of supply situations may be able to manage risk better in a strategic alliance. Purchasers must consider strategic importance of the component, the complexity of the component-product interface, the number of component suppliers available, and the uncertainty of the supplier relationship.  "},{"question":"A group of supply chain partners share information about production and delivery schedules and available transportation assets to accomplish greater efficiencies. This best describes a","choices":["A. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network. ","  B. third-party logistics (3PL) company. ","  C. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. ","  D. distributor integration (DI) network."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A collaborative transportation network allows trading partners to share their transportation assets through aligning transportation needs with assets in real time.  "},{"question":"\"Crafting products/services to increase customer value, potential for added value, competitive differentiation, and increased profit.\" This describes which component of a CRM strategy?","choices":["A. Price ","  B. Product ","  C. Placement ","  D. Promotion"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The product component of a CRM strategy refers to all those actions taken to craft products and services that relate to customer needs, opportunities to add value in the supply chain and enhance competitive position, and still meet profit objectives.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about CRM strategy components is true?","choices":["A. The starting point for product design is the customer. ","  B. Promotion in CRM is distinctly different from traditional marketing strategies. ","  C. Price is determined primarily by the cost of production. ","  D. Placement is determined primarily by product specifications. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Successful product designs begin with knowledge of the customer's needs and buying habits. Promotional activities are greatly supported and enhanced by CRM abilities, but promotion decisions, goals, and activities are, for the most part, unchanged from the traditional marketing model. Price may be determined by a number of factors, as may placement.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the best example of risk mitigation in a strategic alliance?","choices":["A. Surmounting limited availability of component suppliers. ","  B. Improving overall financial position. ","  C. Improving operations by lowering system costs. ","  D. Overcoming barriers to market entry."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"From a purely reactive stance, companies with certain types of supply situations may be able to manage risk better in a strategic alliance. Purchasers must consider the strategic importance of the component, the complexity of the component-product interface, the number of component suppliers available, and the uncertainty of the supplier relationship.  "},{"question":"The five best practices for supply chains include which of the following?","choices":["A. Maximizing profits ","  B. Outsourcing operations and logistics ","  C. Advertising and sales analysis ","  D. Strategic sourcing and supplier management "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The five best practices for supply chains are strategic sourcing and supplier management, operations and logistics, customer relationship management and channels, information technology, and change management.  "},{"question":"\"Customers provide input into what they want the business to be selling.\" This activity occurs during which phase of the product life cycle?","choices":["A. Development ","  B. Introduction ","  C. Growth ","  D. Maturity"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"During the development phase of the product life cycle, CRM businesses research customer needs and expectations and incorporate this research into product design and the entire CRM strategy (i.e., price, placement, promotional message).  "},{"question":"An external data network is","choices":["A. a network resulting from collaboration between the information and communication systems of a company and other members of its supply chain. ","  B. an information repository for purchased customer data. ","  C. an outsourced CRM information management system. ","  D. any information system outside the business from which it may have to extract customer data. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"External data networks are created through collaboration of partners in a supply chain and facilitate the exchange and analysis of information gathered at various points in the supply chain, from factory through distribution to call centers.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about virtual organizations is correct?","choices":["A. Customers perceive the member organizations as distinct entities. ","  B. Individual organizations must preserve their own identity and integrity. ","  C. Information belonging to member organizations remains proprietary. ","  D. Member organizations retain their original, distinctive cultures and values. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"In a virtual organization, there is integration of many systems and extensive sharing of information, often proprietary information. Forming virtual organizations thus requires trust and a cultural shift that embraces the common identity of the virtual organization. At the same time, the member organizations must evaluate the risk of the relationship and preserve their own identity and integrity.  "},{"question":"Maintaining a high level of customer care is critical to CRM brand image promotion, because","choices":["A. Price and placement are no longer of importance to today's service-conscious customer. ","  B. The Internet has given dissatisfied customers the means to make their disloyalty quickly and widely known. ","  C. Brand image awareness has become independent of product satisfaction. ","  D. Customer loyalty no longer extends from an individual product to the supplier of that product. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Dissatisfied customers have the means to make their disloyalty very well-known by the Internet. Complaints posted on Web sites, Web logs, chat rooms, or electronic bulletin boards can have a significant impact on today's Internet-savvy customer and can destroy a once-strong business relationship.  "},{"question":"A company manages catalog purchasing of stationery products and computer equipment for corporate headquarters. It provides invoicing to its clients by requisitioning department customers and delivers product. This best describes a","choices":["A. distributor integration (DI) network. ","  B. third-party logistics (3PL) company. ","  C. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. ","  D. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"This company is probably a third-party logistics provider, a company that performs all or part of an organization's procurement of materials and distribution.  "},{"question":"\"Customer care should, at this stage, promote strong brand identity and development of lifetime customers.\" This sentence best describes what phase of the product life cycle?","choices":["A. Introduction ","  B. Growth ","  C. Maturity ","  D. Decline"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"As sales decline, customer care becomes more critical. As distribution and sales decrease, customers with products that are becoming obsolete must be supported. Success now can win customers loyal to the brand.  "},{"question":"A \"best cost\" risk management outcome is derived by","choices":["A. subtracting cost of possible risk from cost of business. ","  B. multiplying the expected cost of the risk by its likelihood. ","  C. subtracting cost of possible risk from cost of business and dividing that by likelihood of the occurrence. ","  D. adding accumulated risk associated with all strategic suppliers."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A 'best cost\" analysis of risk is performed by multiplying the anticipated cost of the business disruption by the likelihood of its occurrence.  "},{"question":"In which type of customer segmentation are customers grouped by income?","choices":["A. Segmentation by channel ","  B. Segmentation by value ","  C. Segmentation by need ","  D. Segmentation by demographics "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Demographic segmentation groups customers by group characteristics such as age, income, marital status, or family size.  "},{"question":"Which of the following activities would not be useful when implementing an SRM strategy?","choices":["A. Developing a PSA to define deliverables ","  B. Delaying training and corporate communication of the strategy until after pilot program results are identified ","  C. Performing a Pareto analysis of all suppliers ","  D. Conducting a pilot study "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"All those affected by the SRM strategy should be informed and trained before the program is piloted.  "},{"question":"The first step to successfully implement a strategic supplier alliance should be to","choices":["A. align internally by identifying key issues and stakeholders. ","  B. appoint a dedicated alliance manager to oversee the partner relationship. ","  C. select the proper partners by evaluating corporate culture and operating style. ","  D. establish ground rules for how partners will work together and resolve conflict."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Before entering alliances, start identifying key issues and decisions and involving key stakeholders for fewer surprises and greater buy-in by key people.  "},{"question":"You are purchasing an item online and receive the following automated message: \"Other customers like you have also ordered X. Would you like to learn more about this product now? If so, click here.\" This is an example of","choices":["A. up-selling. ","  B. cross-selling. ","  C. a win-back program. ","  D. a loyalty program"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Cross-selling is a CRM tactic made possible by the accumulation of data about a customer's buying habits. Customers are offered related products in addition to their current purchase.  "},{"question":"A supplier tracks shipments and sales and commits to ensuring that retailers have goods on hand. Retailers do not issue purchase orders. This describes","choices":["A. a quick response inventory management model. ","  B. a continuous replenishment inventory management model. ","  C. a vendor-managed inventory model. ","  D. none of the above."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"In a continuous replenishment model, suppliers are notified daily of actual sales or warehouse shipments and commit to replenishing inventory without receiving purchase orders.  "},{"question":"A business finds that a dissatisfied customer has created a Web site on which the business and its products are harshly criticized. This situation most likely represents a failure in","choices":["A. managing media for customer communication. ","  B. development of brand identity. ","  C. monitoring of competitive activities. ","  D. none of the above. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Generally, customers who resort to this tactic feel that they have not been heard by the \"offending\" business and that attempts have not been made to address their problems. This is a failure of customer communication and customer care rather than brand identity, specific communication media, or competitors' activities.  "},{"question":"Which of the following best describes what an organization's risk portfolio should do?","choices":["A. Identify those risk costs that can shifted to a partner's portfolio. ","  B. Eliminate risks by predicting their likely sources. ","  C. Identify current risk-prone partnerships that should be severed. ","  D. Balance risks in terms of probability, cost of occurrence, and cost of mitigation."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"After determining the nature and costs of potential disruptions, organizations assemble a desirable risk portfolio that balances risks in terms of probability, cost of occurrence, and cost of mitigation.   "},{"question":"Which of the following supply chain participants is likely to resist initial SCM efforts because they feel that they are lost in the network, never knowing whom to contact or how to check on an order?","choices":["A. Internal ","  B. Supplier ","  C. Customer ","  D. Distributor"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Initially, customers may complain of getting lost in the network and never knowing whom to contact or how to check on an order. This is particularly common when more than one organization is involved in the support of a product or service.  "},{"question":"Which of the following capability improvement goals are proactive reasons for forming a strategic alliance?","choices":["A. Acquiring technological expertise in weaker areas of the company ","  B. Improving time to market or increasing quality ","  C. Acquiring competitive high-tech equipment ","  D. Improving management compensation programs"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Proactive reasons for an organization to consider a strategic alliance are the alliance's ability to add value to products, enable strategic growth, increase market access, strengthen operations, increase organizational expertise, build organizational skills, and enhance financial strength.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about strategic alliances is true?","choices":["A. Despite potential benefits, there has been little growth in the development of strategic alliances. ","  B. Alliances are relationships between two or more partners in the supply chain. ","  C. In alliance relationships, flexibility is not a good thing. Processes must be rigidly followed and enforced. ","  D. Alliance relationships are marked by organizational integration at a few critical points."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Alliance relationships are marked by organization integration at many points in the partners' organizations, from information systems through marketing and sales to finance.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about implementing CRM technology is correct?","choices":["A. Detailed architecture design at an early stage may lead to an inflexible system that is difficult to change. ","  B. Implementation teams should represent technological areas only. ","  C. If technology is optimal, job responsibilities may remain static in the new system. ","  D. Systems should be measured against whether they increase efficiency and meet customer expectations"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Good CRM technology is easy to use and meets customer expectations. Successful implementation of CRM technology rests on a clear, well-thought-out architecture. Rather than inhibiting change, good design enhances integration and lessens the chances of conflicts as the system evolves. Since it may involve redefining jobs, implementation teams should be cross-functional.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about technology and CRM/SRM is true?","choices":["A. Both CRM and SRM are essentially technological. ","  B. The effects of technology are more significant in SRM than CRM. ","  C. Technology plays a supporting role in CRM and SRM. ","  D. All of the above "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"While CRM and SRM are not synonymous with technical tools (they are philosophies and competitive strategies), they are both greatly supported by technological solutions.  "},{"question":"Vendor-managed inventory is an example of a collaborative initiative that can benefit supply chain participants by","choices":["A. reducing costs. ","  B. shortening production times. ","  C. enhancing demand. ","  D. lengthening intervals between restocking."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"In this arrangement, the manufacturer receives better information about market demand, enabling more efficient production and better inventory management, thereby reducing costs.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about SRM technology is true?","choices":["A. SRM technology can increase visibility of the entire supply chain. ","  B. SRM technology should be used to automate the sourcing process itself. ","  C. The Internet has greatly increased the complexity of SRM technology. ","  D. SRM technology is often too costly for many businesses to implement."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"SRM technology has made it easier to see what is happening at each point of the supply chain in real time. It can streamline many strategic sourcing tasks, but it should not substitute for the judgment required to select sources. The Internet has helped connect the supply chain and simplify communication in SRM systems and the performance of SRM tasks. New SRM technology is increasingly modular and compatible with existing applications and is therefore financially feasible in some form for most companies.  "},{"question":"Supply chain participant priorities often conflict. Which of the following groups sets a priority on product and feature variety and price reduction?","choices":["A. Suppliers ","  B. Manufacturers ","  C. Retailers ","  D. Customers "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Customers demand a variety of products and features as well as low prices.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about outsourcing CRM is true?","choices":["A. CRM should not be outsourced. ","  B. The only good reason for outsourcing CRM is cost savings. ","  C. Separation of CRM vendors should be strictly enforced to protect the outsourcing business's autonomy. ","  D. CRM vendors may provide seamless customer service."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"If CRM vendors train their employees in the client's business and products and if they have adequate resources, they can convey the impression of seamless customer service. CRM may be outsourced for various reasons. Cost is not the only consideration; vendors may offer advanced capabilities, for example. Information gained by one vendor should be shared with all vendors to create a learning organization. "},{"question":"Which of the following supply chain participants is likely to resist SCM efforts initially because they feel that they can't trust any of their supply chain partners enough to share valuable data?","choices":["A. Customer ","  B. Distributor ","  C. Internal ","  D. Supplier "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Organizations' internal members are sometimes hesitant initially to trust any of their supply chain partners enough to share what they value as important internal information or data. While most organizations are open to receiving information regarding best practices from partner organizations, they are typically not willing to reciprocate by sharing equal information.  "},{"question":"Creation of brand image is a concern related to","choices":["A. product. ","  B. placement. ","  C. promotion. ","  D. pricing. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Pricing, product, and placement are all important strategy elements in implementing and maintaining brand image or identity, but creation of the desired image is a promotional activity.  "},{"question":"Which of the following best describes the critical difference between traditional and current supply chain management approaches?","choices":["A. The focus has shifted from human resource-based solutions to technology-driven solutions. ","  B. The focus has shifted from inventory management to demand enhancement. ","  C. The focus has shifted from brick-and-mortar solutions to Web-based solutions. ","  D. The focus has shifted from internal quality improvement and cost reduction to collaborative solutions up and down the supply chain."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"While in the past the strategic focus for many organizations was to improve their internal quality and reduce costs, the new focus is on implementing total supply chain solutions that require collaboration from partner organizations both upstream and downstream.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a good example of a virtual organization?","choices":["A. Raw materials supplier that agrees to supply product for an upcoming production cycle ","  B. Company that sells only services, not products ","  C. Strategic alliance of four companies to develop a new drug product and market it under the name of one of the companies ","  D. Merger of two competitors "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A virtual organization is a long-term strategic alliance of separate business entities that presents itself to third parties as a single entity.  "},{"question":"An SCM partner organization that measures supply chain sales, shipments, and stockouts is adhering to which of the following collaborative principles?","choices":["A. Use supply chain assets collectively. ","  B. Continuously improve. ","  C. Understand the needs of the partners. ","  D. Monitor performance. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"An effective collaborative strategy must be measured to ensure its effectiveness. Processes and systems must be in place to monitor performance. Important measurements include supply chain sales, shipments, stockouts, invoicing, and payments.  "},{"question":"What is the correct term for a CRM tactic described as \"an analytical model to identify vulnerable customers\"?","choices":["A. Data mining ","  B. Loyalty programs ","  C. Win-back programs ","  D. Predictive churn"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Predictive churn uses data about individual customer transactions and histories to identify trends that indicate that a customer may switch to a competitor or cease being a customer. As a result, the vulnerable customer may be offered incentives, such as loyalty programs. The data used in the model may be gathered through data mining.  "},{"question":"A company fears that it will be overcome in the marketplace by a competitor who is developing a new technology that will give it dominance. In response, the company forms an alliance with a supply chain partner. They invest equally in creating the infrastructure to support the alliance, revise their corporate visions and organizational structure, and create processes to share information and merge workflows. Yet, the alliance may fail because it lacks","choices":["A. investment. ","  B. integration. ","  C. individual excellence. ","  D. information."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Successful alliances begin from a position of mutual strength and excellence. In this case, one partner is driven primarily by a desire to escape the problem of looming competition. This will be a hard obstacle to overcome even though the partners have invested in the relationship and integrated their organizations.  "},{"question":"An effective customer service management strategy includes which of the following?","choices":["A. Delivering consistent and identical customer service to all customer segments ","  B. Restricting customer interactions to a limited set of defined scenarios that may be performed within the existing infrastructure ","  C. Development of a product and service agreement (PSA) ","  D. Developing a general system but allowing flexibility to customer service personnel to develop specific procedures "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Development of the PSA, procedures to handle all customer interactions, infrastructure (people and information) to perform the procedures, and metrics to measure success are all parts of a successful customer service management strategy. Customer interaction scenarios are determined by customer needs, not by existing infrastructure. Specific responses should be developed and followed. Service levels may be customized for different customer segments.  "},{"question":"Which of the following benefits applies to lifetime customers?","choices":["A. They increase total marketing costs. ","  B. They are more difficult to satisfy than first-time or short-term customers. ","  C. They tend to have a null effect on revenue but a positive effect on profit. ","  D. They increase the need for CRM activities."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Lifetime customers increase the need for CRM, but they also make it a little easier as the business learns more about them over time. Total marketing costs decline, satisfaction increases with better customer understanding, and both revenue and profit increase.  "},{"question":"A company invites key business customers to participate in the performance evaluations of its account managers. This is an example of","choices":["A. supply chain integration. ","  B. measuring customer satisfaction. ","  C. collaborative management practices. ","  D. voice of the customer information gathering."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Measurement of customer satisfaction is a key element of CRM. B2B companies may measure the CRM effectiveness of their account managers by inviting the managers' customers to participate in their performance evaluations. VOC is considered a more general research tool.  "},{"question":"SRM increases the visibility of the entire supply chain. This benefits SRM participants in which of the following ways?","choices":["A. Enables faster response and better contingency planning ","  B. Lowers the number of required distributors ","  C. Simplifies market segmentation ","  D. Reduces customer service calls "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Increased supply chain visibility can lessen the bullwhip effect and enable early problem detection, faster response and better contingency planning, and stronger relationships because of increased trust.  "},{"question":"Which of the following factors has led to strategic sourcing and greater integration in the supply chain?","choices":["A. Decreasing customer response time ","  B. Shrinking global markets ","  C. Greater fragmentation on both sides of the supply chain ","  D. Commodity pricing"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Commodity pricing has made it more important for businesses to streamline the supply chain and become more cost-effective. The supply chain has, in fact, consolidated rather than fragmented; global markets have grown rather than shrunk. Consolidation may necessitate strategic sourcing as the number of sources narrows. Growing global markets present opportunities but also costs and risks that must be managed. "},{"question":"The cost considerations that SCM partner organizations must examine include all of the following except","choices":["A. Are there consulting fees involved? ","  B. What are the overhead expenses? ","  C. How profitable are each of the partner SCM organizations? ","  D. What are the hardware expenses?"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Cost considerations that SCM partner organizations must examine include costs of hardware, software, overhead, and consulting fees. "},{"question":"How does supply chain integration help resolve the conflict between greater product variety and reduced inventory demand?","choices":["A. By enabling direct warehouse-to-customer shipping ","  B. By reducing lead times ","  C. By enabling delayed differentiation ","  D. By combining shipments through cross-docking "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Shipping generic products and creating the customer variations further down the supply chain (delayed differentiation) aggregates customer demand across all products. This produces a more accurate demand forecast with a smaller degree of variability, allowing reduced storage of safety stock. "},{"question":"Which of the following is an example of a loyalty program?","choices":["A. Customer profiling system ","  B. Free shipping for high-volume customers ","  C. Introductory rates ","  D. \"Buy one, get two\" offer"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A loyalty program simultaneously rewards repeat or high-value customers and encourages continued business through special incentives.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about successful strategic supplier relationships is true?","choices":["A. Although marketplace change may be constant, the details of the relationship should not change. ","  B. The best change occurs in large movements that motivate the entire organization rather than in smaller increments. ","  C. No single restructuring of processes will be adequate. ","  D. Relationships should not be affected by the shifting priorities of the partners."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Supply partners must accept and commit to the fact of change in their relationships. As conditions and individual priorities and strategies change, the processes that define the relationship should change as well. It is better if change can be accomplished incrementally.  "},{"question":"Inventory status, capacity status and plans, production schedules, and shipment and demand forecasts are all shared by all parties on a real-time, online basis. This best exemplifies which of the following distinctions between traditional purchasing and strategic sourcing?","choices":["A. Limited visibility versus entire supply chain visibility ","  B. Transactional versus collaborative ","  C. Purchase price versus true cost ","  D. Boundary-specific versus realigned work processes and workflows "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"When information from suppliers, manufacturers, distributors, retailers, and customers is available for analysis, there is enhanced visibility of the supply chain and opportunities for improvement. Demand information, inventory status, capacity status, capacity plans, production schedules, promotion plans, shipment forecasts, and demand forecasts are all shared and ideally can be accessed by all parties on a real-time, online basis.  "},{"question":"After selecting the proper partner, the next step in creating a successful alliance is to","choices":["A. appoint an alliance manager. ","  B. engage in a collaborative corporate mindset. ","  C. negotiate a win-win deal. ","  D. establish ground rules."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Before the rules, supervision, and improvement of the relationship can be pursued, a win-win deal must be negotiated. This sets the tone for the future alliance.  "},{"question":"Suppliers are folded into the purchasing entity, business goals are shared, and competition has been eliminated. This best exemplifies which of the following types of business relationships?","choices":["A. Ongoing relationship ","  B. Buy the market ","  C. Mergers and acquisitions ","  D. Collaborations/strategic alliance"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"In mergers and acquisitions, suppliers are folded into the purchasing entity. Business goals are shared; business areas participate in setting strategy and planning integration of capabilities, processes, and information. Competition has been eliminated.  "},{"question":"In this long-term arrangement, suppliers are fully aware of the purchaser's goals and strategies and work with the purchaser to develop and implement tactics. This best exemplifies which of the following types of business relationships?","choices":["A. Ongoing relationship ","  B. Buy the market ","  C. Collaborations/strategic alliance ","  D. Mergers and acquisitions "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Collaborations or strategic alliances are long-term arrangements ruled more by agreements than contracts. The suppliers are fully aware of the purchaser's goals and strategies and work with the purchaser to develop and implement tactics. Trust levels are high.  "},{"question":"A purchaser and its suppliers form an ongoing relationship in which they all participate in improving the system. This best exemplifies which of the following distinctions between traditional purchasing and strategic sourcing?","choices":["A. Limited visibility versus entire supply chain visibility ","  B. Boundary-specific versus realigned work processes and workflows ","  C. Purchase price versus true cost ","  D. Transactional versus collaborative"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Traditional purchasing sees each purchase as a discrete transaction. Since strategic sourcing involves ongoing relationships, there is opportunity for collaboration between the purchaser and suppliers that can result in improving the profitability of the supply chain and adding value to the final product or service.  "},{"question":"Central to implementing an SRM strategy is the use of PSAs (product and service agreements). Which of the following statements about PSAs between strategic partners is correct?","choices":["A. The negotiated PSA must be mutually beneficial for both partners. ","  B. The PSA is not subject to standard strategic goal metrics. ","  C. PSAs should be standardized for all suppliers. ","  D. The PSA is crafted only after a carefully conducted pilot program. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A PSA between partners should be mutually beneficial. It may be customized, should precede pilot and full implementation, and should always be measured for improvement.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a benefit associated with customer segmentation?","choices":["A. Lower production costs ","  B. Shorter sales cycle ","  C. Better ROI on promotion budgets ","  D. Shorter time-to-market"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Customer segmentation allows businesses to learn customer desires and habits and design more effective promotional programs.  "},{"question":"Which of the following component purchasing goals are reactive or defensive reasons for forming a strategic alliance?","choices":["A. The number of suppliers able to provide the component ","  B. Opening new markets ","  C. Adding value to products ","  D. Building organizational expertise "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"From a purely reactive stance, companies with certain types of supply situations may be able to manage risk better in a strategic alliance. Purchasers must consider strategic importance of the component, the complexity of the component-product interface, the number of component suppliers available, and the uncertainty of the supplier relationship.  "},{"question":"Which of the following supply chain participants is likely to resist SCM efforts because they feel that e-marketplaces have the effect of reducing their products and services to a commodity?","choices":["A. Internal ","  B. Customer ","  C. Supplier ","  D. Distributor"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Many suppliers feel that e-marketplaces have the effect of reducing their products and services to a commodity where price is emphasized rather than quality or the partnership.  "},{"question":"The Internet and intranets have benefited supplier relationship management through improved communication. Which of the following represents a benefit of the Internet and intranets to SRM?","choices":["A. Early detection of quality problems through timely information sharing ","  B. Better forecasting of raw materials and labor through synchronized planning activities ","  C. Decreased time-to-market through coordinating workflows ","  D. All of the above "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Improved, real-time communication can benefit supply relationships in all of the ways listed, from planning through production and distribution.  "},{"question":"Supply chain participant priorities often conflict. Which of the following groups sets a priority on flexible delivery times, large volumes, and consistent materials mixes?","choices":["A. Logistics managers ","  B. Retailers ","  C. Suppliers ","  D. Warehouse managers "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Suppliers of raw materials typically prefer flexible delivery times, large yet stable volume demands, and consistency in mix of materials.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about vendor-managed inventory is true?","choices":["A. Retailers maintain oversight on ordering. ","  B. Retailers have no hand in setting initial inventory; historical data are used. ","  C. Inventory data cannot be tied to MPS or MRP. ","  D. Inventory levels can be adjusted according to different variables. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Although vendors may suggest inventory levels, retailers must approve initial levels. After that point, levels will be maintained by the vendor according to an agreement and models based on POS and shipment data for greatest customer satisfaction and return on inventory. Data can be tied into planning processes so that MPSs can be created and MRPs set.  "},{"question":"In an SCM implementation effort, the channel master is","choices":["A. the person who designates the optimal communications channels. ","  B. the organization that drives the implementation process. ","  C. the organization that designates the optimal delivery channels. ","  D. the person designated as strategic team leader. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Designating one organization as channel master positioned at the center of the initiative during its inception can contribute to the strategy's success. The channel master should be capable of rallying supporters and driving the implementation beyond the preoccupation with improving internal competencies.  "},{"question":"\"A variety of activities all designed to position what the business is selling to the right people, at the right time, and in the right manner.\" This describes which component of a CRM strategy?","choices":["A. Price ","  B. Placement ","  C. Promotion ","  D. Product "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Promotion comprises a variety of marketing activities, from customer research through strategy setting and advertising. CRM enhances both the gathering of information about customers and the use of that information in marketing activities.  "},{"question":"A customer-focused business","choices":["A. gathers information about the customer but restricts its use to critical points in the supply chain. ","  B. focuses on customer care rather than product/service design and delivery. ","  C. restricts communication and distribution channels to the most profitable options. ","  D. educates customers throughout the purchasing process"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Customer-focused businesses try to make their customers feel better educated about what they are buying before, during, and after the purchase. They promote sharing of information about the customer throughout the supply chain, appreciate the need to consider customer needs in designing as well as marketing and distributing products, and maintain communication and distribution strategies that value convenience for the customer more than profitability. "},{"question":"Which of the following statements about the challenges of implementing CRM and SRM strategies is true?","choices":["A. Managers must acquire new skill sets. ","  B. Decision making must become more centralized and uniform. ","  C. Technology is too complex and expensive. ","  D. None of the above "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"As structures and processes change, managers will need to acquire new skills to support implementation of SRM and CRM. Decision making will actually move downward throughout the organization, closer to critical points in the supply chain. Technology is increasingly available, powerful, and easy to integrate.  "},{"question":"Establishing clear ground rules for collaboration and conflict resolution benefits both alliance participants by","choices":["A. providing clear channels of legal redress for each participant. ","  B. ensuring strict adherence to the established alliance contract by both participants. ","  C. preventing any sources of tension between participant organizations. ","  D. encouraging participants to redefine problematic connections rather than break them. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"In a dynamic marketplace, a static consultant contract without clear and flexible guidelines and processes to manage the relationship simply encourages consultants to break their connection with the company rather than redefine it. "},{"question":"An example of a supplier performance reporting mechanism is","choices":["A. a floor failure event rate. ","  B. a certification document. ","  C. an automated performance alert. ","  D. a rejected materials rate."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Rates, such as number of floor failures, rejected materials, or delays in shipment, are used to compile reports of supplier performance but are not themselves reports. Reporting mechanisms include such tools as scorecards, performance failure alerts (which are online and in real time), and surveys. A certification indicates that a supplier has met criteria but does not report ongoing performance.  "}]